germayne: Okay, can you guys, can you guys hear me?
germayne: Can you hear me? Okay, good evening, good evening, everyone. We'll start in about 2 minutes' time.
germayne: How do you guys feel? Do you guys feel good? Is it, is it public holiday for…
germayne: Is it public holiday tomorrow for most of you guys?
germayne: He is right.
germayne: Okay.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Good evening, all.
germayne: Yeah, good evening, good evening, Jaya.
Kim Meng Phoa: We can enjoy the public holiday.
germayne: Sorry, sorry.
Kim Meng Phoa: Possible to end our lesson earlier, so that we can enjoy the public holiday?
germayne: Oh… I will, I will do my best, I will do my best.
germayne: Okay?
Soon | NTU: If we can, if we can.
germayne: Yeah, if we can, if we can end early with all the topics covered, yes, then we will… we will… we will do so.
germayne: Yeah, I think today's one is okay. I think today's topic is okay.
Kim Meng Phoa: Thank you.
germayne: Yeah, as in, nothing intentional.
germayne: If we can annually, we will annually, okay?
germayne: Okay, I think we can… we can… we can get started.
germayne: Okay, so, good evening.
germayne: I think today is the third last, third last… class for Module 3.
germayne: So, on… on Tuesday, for a recap, Tuesday we talked a lot about neural network. We did a bit on the math of how it works. So for… for today, there wouldn't really be a lot of
germayne: math portion, I think it's really mostly applied, and probably sharing a bit more about the transition from traditional computer vision
germayne: Right? And how does… Deep learning actually influences and…
germayne: is being adapted to make inference on images. And I think we also talked a little bit about, you know, improving some of the training, I think will also be part of today's lesson.
germayne: Okay, so I think we are at… we are almost towards the end.
germayne: next… next Tuesday, for NLP, again, we'll go through the basics of NLP. Then, for the final… final class, we will then relate deep learning back to NLP, okay? So for today, we will focus on the inference of images.
germayne: How do we actually make use of what we have seen in neural network? And we are going to be introducing additional components to these building blocks.
germayne: So that we can actually, you know, take advantage of certain properties that we know about images in order to actually train models that will be really good at making prediction for image data.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so today's goal is really… I think we will… we will talk a bit about some of the… the motivation, I think from an intuition perspective, and then you will then see from the notebook how do you actually apply CNN, right, which is what we call convolutional neural networks.
germayne: And finally, we will then talk a little… we'll give this idea of
germayne: Actually utilizing pre-trained models, or what we call transfer learning, and that will actually serve for the foundation for deep learning in the applied side of things.
germayne: Okay, so I think on… on… on Tuesday, what we are… what we have seen is we have seen…
germayne: the basic building blocks from neural networks, and if you guys remember, actually, we were able to make use of the… what we call the fit-forward neural network, which is essentially just the basic building blocks.
germayne: All you have are just essentially linear layers, and then we added some nonlinear components in order to make the overall neural network more expressive.
germayne: Right, we saw that. And actually, if you guys remember, in the notebook, we actually applied the notebook on image data. You guys remember, right? On Tuesday.
germayne: Correct? We actually applied image data on neural network. So maybe at this point in time, the question will be that, okay.
germayne: So what… what has changed, right? So what you have seen… what we will… what I will try to give you the intuition is that later on, we will add… we will add some additional components in order to capture certain properties
germayne: which we want the model to directly have access to. And what I mean by that is later on, you will see why neural network is actually very powerful for unstructured data, right?
germayne: the LEGO blocks are so customizable that it actually captures, and what we call, you know, the resulting architecture actually has what we call this inductive bias, right, which is really good for specific unstructured data.
germayne: So, of course, you can reshape and flatten your image data, as you've seen in your notebook on Tuesday. You can just flatten it, and ultimately, from three-dimension, you can always flatten the data.
germayne: to two dimensions, right? Because in your fit-forward neural network, again, this is not a very… this is not a true statement, right? But at least on Tuesday, what you have is you've seen that you have some kind of image data you have to hide, width, and then you have the channel. So basically, you can just
germayne: Combine… you can combine one of… you can basically combine the last two.
germayne: Dimension into a single dimension. So basically, you're just combining it to be something like that.
germayne: Oh, sorry, actually, in fact, you combine all of it.
germayne: You flatten all of it into a single dimension, so actually you have four dimensions.
germayne: Bye bit.
germayne: Right, so for your original data, you actually have n by height, by width by channel, because this is the number of image that you have. So in your notebook, right, we actually sort of flattened this into a tabular data.
germayne: So it's n by height times… width times channel. So that's actually what you did on Tuesday. And you'll notice that later on, I'm going to show the intuition why this is actually not that good. But the idea here is that neural network doesn't really know, doesn't really care, but…
germayne: if you try to just flatten it, you might not be making best use of the image property itself, right? And you will see later on why the convolutional neural network that was created by Yin Le Kun
germayne: actually performs very well for image… image data. So today, right, we are just talking about computer vision. Computer vision is not just deep learning, by the way, right? When people think about computer vision, essentially, how do you make inference on image? How do you pre-process images, actually has been… has been around for quite… quite… quite some time.
germayne: And there has been, like, traditional methods that people use in order to make certain inference on image. So it's not just because, oh, you know, image analysis or computer vision doesn't exist before deep learning.
germayne: It is just that with deep learning, instead of doing rule-based or, you know, using a lot of this manual method, you can now build neural networks in order to
germayne: Predict certain stuff using the image data.
germayne: Okay? So, of course, you can see that
germayne: Ultimately, at a very basic level, you can see that we can, you know.
germayne: formulate the problem as the input data using image, right? Again, you can formulate it back to a classification problem or a regression problem, right? You still want to predict certain stuff.
germayne: And of course, you can also go very deep into image, or what we call object detection.
germayne: But obviously, the object detection is not in the topic today. We're just talking solely from, given certain image data, how do we actually make inference, regression, or classification output using certain target label?
germayne: Okay, I'm not gonna go too far back, but…
germayne: obviously, as I mentioned, computer vision has been around for quite some time. It's not because of deep learning. I think Yan Le Kun, I can't remember when he created Convolution Neural Network, I think it's probably very long ago. I think probably in the 90s, if I remember. Yeah, but… but he… he… he was the one that popularized
germayne: And created this specific block called the convolutional neural network, which essentially allows us to train
germayne: the data using image… sorry, trained neural networks specifically.
germayne: And in… in using this.
germayne: block that he created, this specific architect… this specific, what do I call it? This specific… think of it like a specific LEGO block, right, that he created. He actually improved training on image data.
germayne: And of course, fast forward today, obviously today, we have sort of moved away from convolution neural network, right, just recently, but convolution neural network still works for a lot of the problem statements, so it's not like, it's not like it's useless.
germayne: Okay, so obviously, with deep learning, the, the, the…
germayne: The extent that we can push on training image data has actually evolved.
germayne: Okay, so I already mentioned these are some of the applications. Obviously, one of the very useful use cases is actually called OCR, right? Basically, if I have an image, if I have certain characters on an image, can I actually just convert them? So essentially, I want the model to predict
germayne: and output the text, right? If I'm able to recognize it from an image. So there's a lot of use case for OCRs, right? If, let's say, your companies
germayne: have certain documentation, you want to use OCR, right? Very, very common application that, you know, maybe you want to convert PDF documents into a format, text-based format. Or maybe if, let's say, for my example, we are always very interested in preserving maps.
germayne: in terms of how do I actually encode all the information in the real world into some kind of data. Of course, we also use OCR.
germayne: then,
germayne: I think… I think next week we'll talk a bit about NLP, but NLP basically makes us, in terms of, like, how do we think about
germayne: outputting text, right, from a… from a… sorry, from a basic standpoint, it's like, how do we think about processing text data? But then later on, we'll talk about how does this actually translate to deep learning? Which, obviously, you guys know that one of the use cases is the large language model.
germayne: Okay, so these are just some examples. A lot of tools, I'm sure you guys will know that there's some form of OCR involved. Oh, sorry, some kind of computer vision involved. If you guys have things like your… not sure if you guys have this, so maybe, let's say, you buy some kind of cameras.
germayne: for your… for your house, for example, you notice that they have some kind of features where they can detect whether the person is a human, or if there's a puzzle, or stuff like that, right? So basically, this all uses computer vision.
germayne: Okay, so we are not going to go very deep into object detection, right? So today, right, you will see that what we are going to focus on is, given certain image input, we are just going to, you know, predict whether if it's
germayne: A classification problem, or if you want to predict certain continuous value, right?
germayne: But then, actually, for other applications of computer vision, you can actually do object detection. So, obviously, whatever that we go through today would still be relevant, but there's going to be some slight difference in the architecture itself. So here, usually, you want to make some kind of prediction at
germayne: pixel level, right? So you essentially have things like a bounding box, you have to predict,
germayne: the bounding box itself has to decide where the object is, and within the object, it has another kind of classification, right, what it is. So, you can see that one of the very famous models that people tend to use is actually this border called YOLO, which allows you to do multiple classes.
germayne: But then… but then people are so smart that nowadays there are other types of model that allows you to predict an unlimited number of classes.
germayne: Of course, we will not talk about that today. If we have time, probably we can talk about it, at the end of the class, I think the last lesson. When you guys have everything, maybe I can share a bit more about, like, how this has evolved.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, obviously, for object detection, a lot of it, medical, people try to detect certain areas, you know, given, like, your CT scan and stuff, given some kind of medical data. You can also have your autonomous vehicles, right?
germayne: retail, surveillance, I think this is the one I mentioned. And yeah, so there's basically a lot of application for object detection.
germayne: Okay, so I think the important thing here is to also start to understand that
germayne: When we think all about deep learning, or rather, when we think about all the algorithms that we have learned so far, it does not process data the way human does.
germayne: And I think I sort of…
germayne: mentioned this, I think, very briefly, that if you think about… if you think about it under the hood, right, even if you go through what we have done on Tuesday, the model itself does not know. The model doesn't really know, right? We are usually… we are… we are essentially using some kind of
germayne: quantitative metric in order to direct the model, right? We talked a bit about this in backpropagation, right? I've shown the math that
germayne: ultimately, you are just passing the gradient, the upstream gradient, from the laws all the way back to each of the building blocks, right? So it doesn't really know, and if you think about it from an image perspective, the model doesn't really have a concept of how human thinks. Of course.
germayne: you will see later that what was very brilliant about CNN, when I say CNN, it's basically the convolutional neural network, you will actually see that
germayne: When humans try to create that algorithm, there are some thoughts put into it that tries to mimic how humans perceive.
germayne: Right? And these are actually very useful in creating these kind of inventions that works, right? You saw on Tuesday that, you know, when you think about the way neural network interacts, right, even though mathematically it's just really dot product.
germayne: across each of the blocks, but you guys saw that, you know, the very famous illustration you guys were seeing, that we have the… we have the neurons, right, and each of the neurons are interacting with them. But under the hood, we know it's just W1, W2, you know, and we're just doing dot product, but…
germayne: The point here is that people tried to emulate something from humans, right? The neurons was, like, emulating how our neurons actually
germayne: interact with each of the neurons. Like, together, they… individually, they might not do anything, but together, they can make certain inference. So similarly for images, you will start to, you know.
germayne: be very familiar with this idea that ultimately they're just data. Image is essentially, if you really think about it, like what I mentioned, the height, width, and channel, this is basically just a three-dimensional matrix.
germayne: Right.
germayne: I have mentioned that when you come to computer vision, you need to be very familiar and comfortable with working with a n-dimension matrix.
germayne: Right? So, if you think about this.
germayne: The image itself has a height, a width, you guys are familiar with that, and actually, it has typically 3 color channels.
germayne: You'll start to see later that the model will just perceive this as a matrix, and later on, we will start to manipulate these and project them to other dimensions.
germayne: Okay? So essentially, the computer is really just saying matrix. Similarly, right, I'm going to give a bit of, like, a prelude to next week. Similarly, when you're talking to a large language model, you need to understand that the large language model doesn't really know what you're saying, right?
germayne: It ultimately processes the encoded text, has some form of tokens.
germayne: And these tokens are similar, you know, you can think of it as… it's just encoded with certain information, and its goal is to just make some kind of prediction.
germayne: Okay? So, doesn't really see what you guys think it is seeing, right? It's essentially just… and you can see here, this is the tree value. So, those of you that don't know that images actually consist of this tree channel, then today, you know, right? These three RGB channels.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So I think I won't go very deep into here, but, you know, there are some traditional… traditional computer vision techniques that people have been really working on. You think a lot about
germayne: manipulating the color spaces, you can also do certain filtering, and of course, most importantly, age detection. Actually, age detection is still very relevant, I would say. The idea here is there are certain mathematical properties that you can apply on, and, you know, we will talk about that.
germayne: later, where you can actually, you know, smoothen the image, you could obviously convert the image and then detect certain ages. Okay, these are where the classical computer vision techniques is actually done.
germayne: Okay, so you can see that there's the color spaces. You can actually convert from the original 3-channel image into each of these different color spaces, right? And this is actually how traditional computer vision actually
germayne: make certain kind of inference. You can see most of the library is actually using this library called OpenCV, so it has all the transformation that you need to do. You don't have to write… you don't have to write the code from scratch.
germayne: Okay, I'm just going to… I'm just going to skip some of these, but essentially, there are some color spaces, you probably will see in your… in your notebook later on, right, where we are able to map the original data into each of these different color spaces.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Not super important. And then, of course, there are… there are certain filtering that is also done on the image data. So essentially, you can apply some kind of smoothing, blurring, you can sharpen the data, you can do edge detection.
germayne: right? You can do a Gaussian blur. Essentially, you will see it's actually applying a… a process that is known as the… either we call it the cross…
germayne: cross…
germayne: sorry, convolution or cross-correlation. Essentially, we are able to use some kind of matrix, and we are going to apply some kind of transformation technique to apply that on the data.
germayne: Right, on your image data. So basically, there's this concept called the kernel, which we will talk about it later. And… fun fact, actually, we talk about this concept in 3.6.
germayne: Anybody remembers what is in 3.6?
germayne: What is in 2.6?
Zac Ang: time series.
germayne: Time series, yes. So, you see, right, what I love about all these different things that we talk about is that you realize that there's bits and pieces that will be relevant, correct? So, you will see later why I brought up time series, okay?
germayne: So we'll talk about this process called convolution.
germayne: Right? And actually, convolution is the same process as the cross-correlation, but today, for today's sake, we'll just talk solely about convolution.
germayne: Okay, anybody has any questions before I… Move on.
germayne: I think you guys are memeing, right? Okay. So, I think I'll continue.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so, essentially the idea of convolution, you will see later, is that we want to apply some kind of kernel onto your data, and the interesting thing here is that the type of kernel that you apply, right? For now, you might not know what I'm talking about, but the type of kernel that you apply actually can influence the output of the image. So you can basically see this is the… this is the kernel.
germayne: This is the cono.
germayne: Right?
germayne: So essentially, the idea you will see later, how do we actually do the application? And each of these, actually, mathematically, they are able to transform the pixel from the original data space.
germayne: And they're actually able to result in some kind of output that has that property. So you can see Gaussian is basically like the… they call the kernel the La Prussian kernel.
germayne: So basically, it's like the Laplace, distribution, looks something like that. But, of course, in two dimensions. I can't draw this in two dimensions here, but…
germayne: But this is, like, what the traditional… this is what the traditional computer vision techniques actually do.
germayne: You will start to see later how does this actually relate to… to deep learning, okay?
germayne: Okay, then, obviously, you also have age detection, so basically, we can apply the same, and again, with some specific kernel, you can actually get the ages of the… of the pixels. And why this is actually very important is because, traditionally, in the past.
germayne: people use edge detection in order to, you know, understand some of the differences of the color that's actually changing between the pixel, and because you are able to detect the edge, right, you can, you know, make some kind of interesting inference on the data itself, right? So that's actually, in the past, how people actually do it.
germayne: But now, of course, you have deep learning. You can directly teach the model to make certain kind of prediction directly on the image. You do not have to manually, you know.
germayne: Enforce this concept of converting the image data into the… into the edge, okay?
germayne: So you can see these are some of the example of very common age detection algorithm, really classical, traditional computer vision. So you can see these are the different output, where, given an image data, you can actually convert the edge
germayne: Right? And this edge, this output, of course, you can use it to do other stuff. You can use it to detect if there's a certain change in the boundaries of the data in order to detect whether there's a presence of something.
germayne: Okay, so this is the old school, traditional computer vision.
germayne: Okay, so you can see why is it very important.
germayne: as human beings, right, when we look at an image, we are able to infer that there's an object. And if you think about it, what human being does is that you're actually inferring that there's a change in the pixel value. Essentially, each of the edge itself is a high contrast.
germayne: With the background, right? So you can basically know that, okay, there's actually something here. Or you can actually use age detection to do image segmentation as well.
germayne: Right? Feature extraction in this context is actually done manually, but you will see that the beauty of doing deep learning is that we are actually able to produce feature maps.
germayne: Right?
germayne: One thing to go back to what we talked about on Tuesday, so if you remember on Tuesday when we have a neural network, a block.
germayne: If your data here is 3 by N,
germayne: In this example, again, you are using your Visio Kaggle data. You have 3 different features. Here, your block here, can be something arbitrary, let's say something like 100.
germayne: by 3.
germayne: Right? So WT here, W, transpose here is actually 100 by 3. The output here, you realize, will become
germayne: Hundred.
germayne: Okay, actually, let me… let me delete this.
germayne: So if you do a dot product, right, you realize that there's actually 100 by N.
germayne: You guys saw, right? This is what we saw on Tuesday.
germayne: I think I sort of mentioned a bit about, you know, actually, you can project the data to a higher dimension, or you can project the data to a lower dimension. So you have really seen this on Tuesday, right? So if, let's say, there's a block, the block I choose to have 100,
germayne: dense units, right? So this is the hidden… this is the hidden unit parameter that you guys were asking, right? If you guys remember in the notebook. You can set this arbitrarily to any value, right? Obviously, this is a parameter that you need to decide. The higher the hidden unit, obviously, the more expressive you can learn, right? The more complex function you can learn. But you notice one thing here is that
germayne: I want to talk a bit about this is because you notice that now I'm actually able to project 100… I'm actually able to project the data from… I have n number of samples, I'm actually projecting them to 100 hidden units, right?
germayne: If you think about it, right, the reason for doing this is because the model has its own concept of projecting this to 100.
germayne: you know, it's a… it's a… it's like… think of it like a, you know, a kind of features that you cannot interpret, but from a model perspective, it's actually building features for you, right? So you can see that we're actually projecting, in this example, even for a fit-forward neural network, these 100 hidden units is actually an expression of the data that the model has learned in
germayne: 100 dimension, in a dimension of 100, and a dimension of D equals to 100.
germayne: So similarly, you will see, right, later, when we talk about feature extraction, your initial image.
germayne: Might have only 3 channels, but we are actually able to project them into higher dimension.
germayne: from a human perspective, obviously, these dimensions wouldn't matter, right? You're not able to interpret directly. But it is these dimensions where the model is actually extracting certain key information.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Similarly, you know, if you notice that in our blocks, you can actually project these… and because the neural network is so flexible, right, you can set any amount of hidden units here. You are basically projecting these values to different outputs. So, later on, maybe in your next block, if you choose to have, like, let's say 10 units.
germayne: you're basically projecting from 100 dimensions to 10 dimensions, so each of these dimensions is actually learning something very interesting, right? So, I think I want to get this idea here first.
germayne: Because later on, you will start to see a very, very similar concept for this.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, so far, anybody has any questions?
germayne: Am I confusing you guys?
Zac Ang: I feel like it's a bit confusing. I don't really get it.
germayne: Okay, so I think the takeaway here is that the beauty of using neural networks, right, is that
germayne: why is it that, if I remember correctly, on Tuesday, there was a slide that we sort of talked about that
germayne: Actually, the neural network is actually learning some kind of features. And what makes it so different from other traditional machine learning algorithms is that it's actually able to project
germayne: the original dimension, if you think about it, right? If you think about it, from a human perspective, you guys were given 77 columns. Of course, 76 features, right? With one… actually, am I correct? It's 76 features with one target label. So from a human perspective, you have 76.
germayne: features.
germayne: I recommended you guys on Saturday that, hey man, Jamin said, you know, do a lot of feature engineering, and I can see a lot of groups are doing feature engineering, which is why the leaderboard now is so different.
germayne: The leaderboard now is very different from last week, right?
germayne: Because people were, like, doing feature engineering non-stop. Okay, I don't know. I'm assuming you guys are doing feature engineering. We will see you on Saturday. But the idea is that when you do feature engineering, you are actually trying to extract a lot more signals just from the 76.
germayne: dimension. So, if you think about it, right, if I'm just going to throw, you know, every single column into the data, my dimension is 76. But if you do feature engineering, you can basically engineer, I don't know, maybe, let's say a team engineered 150 features.
germayne: If you think about it, right, if you put this into the model, the dimension is actually 150, correct?
germayne: But, what I've shown just now.
germayne: If you guys remember, again, I used the same expression that we did, so we have X.
germayne: If you do a W1, You apply a nonlinear layer.
germayne: and then you apply a W2. This was basically what we've shown yesterday, right? Exactly the equation, right? But actually, if you look at W multiplied by X, right, the data is actually already projected beyond the dimension that you know. Because the example that I've shown is that the data can be n by 100.
germayne: Depending on the hidden unit. So the original data is no longer… the original data space that you input the data is no longer present, right? It's been projected to 100 features. These 100 features must have some kind of meaning, because ultimately, W
germayne: your W is actually being updated, iterated using this formula, right, if you remember, W minus… At all.
germayne: Okay, I'm so sorry that I never bring my thing here today, but…
germayne: I didn't want to do a lot of math today, that's why I didn't… We have epsilon DL over.
germayne: Okay, pardon my ugly drawing, but you get a point, right? So W is actually learning something. So that means that when I take W1 multiplied by X and project them to 100 by N by 100, the N by 100 cannot be junk.
germayne: You guys understand what I'm trying to say? The M by 100 might have some meaning.
germayne: So when people… when people talk about, like, you know, it's actually…
germayne: extracting feature, or actually getting some kind of feature map, is actually projecting this data, original data that you had, to some kind of higher dimension. And this higher dimension might capture more information.
germayne: By the way, right, the dimension doesn't really matter, doesn't mean 100 means better than 5. But my point is that this dimension is no longer the original data dimension that you had. It's a projection by the neural network.
germayne: Right? You will start to see the same, similar pattern, that actually, in fact, in computer vision, people were able to extract out the weights
germayne: To some extent, and people were able to actually find out that, oh, actually, if I were to visualize some of this internal stuff, actually, I realized that the model is trying to see something.
germayne: And that's actually how people infer that, oh, actually the model is learning.
germayne: Okay, so the point here is that feature extraction, I'm just trying to say.
germayne: all of this is actually being done today. You are already… and there's many terms that people is calling this. If you pass a… if you pass an input into the neural network, you get an output. Essentially, we are calling this encoding, okay? We are called… it's known as encoding the data. We are encoding this data to a new dimension that
germayne: Obviously, you can spend some effort in visualizing it, but this higher dimension actually now has certain features. So to some extent, it's actually learning something abstract that you will not understand.
germayne: Okay, so that's actually what I'm trying to convey.
germayne: Okay, I think I will skip.
germayne: the traditional computer vision for today, but Anybody has any more questions?
germayne: Okay, I know it might be very confusing, right? So sometimes I'm using different terms, and some of these terms actually has a lot of… they are basically alias, or you can think of them as synonyms of each other. So, like, people think about feature map, it's actually encoding, it's the same thing, okay?
germayne: Here is something that helps. Okay, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, actually, that is a, that's a… I think what Grant posts is actually a very, a very good, I think a very good, a very good, what do you call that? It's actually a very good way to think about. So, you know, when people talk about encoding, right?
germayne: It's like, okay, so encoding has a term.
germayne: So when people say encode, right? Encoding is basically just transforming a data from one format into another, if you think about it, right?
germayne: in those examples that you gave, when you do Space64, you are basically encoding using some kind of format. Let's say if today you want to, is there any other…
germayne: Okay, I think Base64 is actually a pretty good example. So essentially, if you do base64, right, any kind of… in any kind of data format you got, your text, you're basically encoding them into this Base64 string. So this string itself represents all your entire data, right? Is it human-readable? Not human-readable, right? Anybody can read Base64, please tell me.
germayne: Okay, anybody, if you can just look at Base64, you can read Base64, you tell me, but essentially, you guys are… you guys have been seeing this
germayne: you know, I think there's a lot… I'm not… again, I'm not sure whether if I can just use some random example, but essentially, a lot of data type. Wait, actually, we talked about encoding in Module 2, right?
germayne: We talked about encoding in Module 2, right? So, in a sense, right, encoding is basically, you know, using some kind of algorithm, we can actually, you know, convert the format
germayne: and change it into another… another encoding format that maybe you, you are not able to read it. I mean, it's not… the point is not for you to read it, but there are some kind of properties. Now, for neural network, it's going to do the encoding.
germayne: the data doesn't change. In this case, all of them are the same representation, they are just all matrices.
germayne: N by whatever, they're always going to be represented. The N… the N is always going to be there, because that's your number of sample, yeah, number of instances. But whatever that you are projecting, if I project them to D, and usually in papers, they put them as D, D1 or D2.
germayne: The D is actually just a dimension that is being encoded into a higher dimension, lower dimension, whatever.
germayne: So what this means is that if you want to do feature compression, you guys learned in one of the modules, I believe it was
germayne: Last week, we talked a bit about PCA, right? I mentioned PCA is just a linear projection.
germayne: But actually, the model has the ability to encode these from a higher space to a lower space. How do you do it? You just control it using your width parameter, which is your dense block, right? If I want the dense unit to be, 5,
germayne: I'm always able to convert the data to 5, a dimension of 5.
germayne: Okay, so actually, yeah, thanks, thanks, Gwen, I think that is a fantastic
germayne: Okay, so I think Brian asked me, is YOLO relevant? Actually, YOLO is still…
germayne: It's still relevant, though, because I can say that it's because recently we did try some… we did try some experiment.
germayne: But I think what changes today, right? I feel like what makes… what makes YOLO
germayne: Rather, what makes it more interesting is that there's actually a lot more ways to formulate object detection, and obviously one very popular method that I'm sure all of you guys know is actually using large language models, right? People are using vision models.
germayne: to put in a text, and then you output the… sorry, put in the image, and then you output the text. In fact, you can output JSON.
germayne: So…
germayne: people are actually doing that, and I think a lot of the open source, smaller models, I believe DeepSig also has an OCR version, that actually is very, very competitive in… in…
germayne: inferencing on image. But I think we might… I think for some of the work that we do, we still try to see whether YOLO works, but actually, we found out that there are other ways that are actually much better than YOLO. But, obviously, YOLO is something that we first tried, to see if out of the box certain stuff works.
germayne: Yeah, but I think there's a lot of options right now compared to YOLO models, yeah.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay? So, okay, so I think, right, what we'll do is we'll leave
germayne: we will leave this to be optional, because this is traditional computer vision. This is… this is… I'm sure you guys can… can just use it, can just go through the first part, so we will not be talking about the… the traditional computer vision. I want to focus more on… back to deep learning.
germayne: Okay? If we have extra time, and you guys, you know, let's say on Saturday, after you guys presented, oh, I'll talk about Saturday later, but after you guys have, you know, done, we are done with Kaggle, we're done with everything, and then if you guys still want, then we can talk about image processing, but I don't think it's that important. I think you can take your time to go through it.
germayne: Okay, so now we want to go into the meat of the actual topic, right? We want to relate this back to deep learning again.
germayne: So again, we want to understand how, you know, we open up some concept, we talk a bit about the convolution, but we haven't talked about it, right?
germayne: So now, we are just going to… we are just going to write on what we have gone through on… on… on Tuesday. Oh, by the way, for Tuesday, I have uploaded the annotated notebook, so you guys already have the annotated notebook. I'm so sorry, I forgot about it.
germayne: So, but anyway, back to today. So…
germayne: I think we want to really understand how does the AI actually understands the image.
germayne: Okay, Vera?
germayne: Sorry, let me stop sharing for a while. Let me do something real quick.
germayne: Okay, so obviously, obviously, I think if you think about how the AI looks at the image, obviously the, the, the problem of
germayne: the image itself is still going to cause some problems. There's still potential challenge that computer vision cannot solve. So I think some of the common ones is occlusion. Basically, the object that you're interested in is actually not covered fully, it's getting blocked, you know, the viewpoint is different.
germayne: Of course, the data that's taken, the light, you know, if you take a photo, there's lighting, light, yeah, then, I think lighting is here, distortion. So, obviously.
germayne: Later, we will talk a bit about certain techniques that people use to train the model in order to, you know, maybe make the model more robust to this potential problem, but I can tell you things like occlusion is still not solvable. If, let's say, there's something that's blocking the person, there's no way the model can be intelligent enough. You know, there's still going to be a high chance of getting it wrong.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay.
germayne: So I think what is… what is interesting here is I'm going to relate this back to what I mentioned earlier on, that actually on Tuesday, we have already sort of trained a… you know, you guys saw that we did it on the toy dataset, right, the MNIS dataset.
germayne: You guys sort of have already seen it, that actually we can flatten the data. So again, this is… this is a three-dimension image, right? Obviously, the three-dimension is not mentioned here, but when we flatten the data, the information is not changed. Basically, we just basically arrange the matrix into
germayne: everything into one column. So now the overall data, including the total number of instants, becomes two-dimensional.
germayne: Okay, I'll repeat again. So, in this example, right, typically your data is a height.
germayne: the height is the number of elements. In this case, it's a 3x3 image. Obviously, that's a channel, 3-channel. So it's going to be a 3x3x3 matrix. 3x3x3 matrix, right? So if you flatten the data, obviously, you're going to have 9 elements here.
germayne: So…
germayne: It's actually, we saw that we can do a n by 9 model, I can put it into my neural network, I can just create a dense block with 100 units, and the weight will be 100x9, and I can still do the output, right? But what's the problem? What's the problem with me doing that? Anybody wants to make a guess.
germayne: What we don't…
germayne: I want to see if you guys have that intuition. So you guys see, right, I can… my matrix here is 100x9.
germayne: So what do you think is the problem? If, you know, if I choose to just flatten the data and put it into a feed-forward neural network?
germayne: Anybody wants to make a guess?
germayne: What do you think is an issue, a potential issue?
germayne: Hypothetically.
germayne: What if I use a 4K image?
germayne: So you guys know 4K pixels, right?
germayne: 4K means what?
Zac Ang: You lose the dimensions.
Zac Ang: The… The 3x3x3.
germayne: No, okay, so in this picture, obviously, the picture very small. But let's say you guys use a very good camera.
germayne: Use a DSLR, you take a photo. Photo very clear, right?
germayne: So when the photo is very clear, what does it mean?
Zac Ang: You've got a lot.
Josiah Ho: more data required.
germayne: More pixels, yeah, okay, so more pixels. So when the pixels is very big, what does it mean?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: more data.
germayne: More… okay, yes, so that means the matrix very big, correct?
germayne: So what happens when I flatten the thing?
germayne: What, what, what is Big Hill?
germayne: This guy, right? You realize?
germayne: So actually, something here feels rough, right? Feels off, right? Okay, by the way, right, of course, this is with the power of hindsight.
germayne: Because somebody created this already.
germayne: So I'm able to say that. But you realize that the number of parameters that's required actually scale with the image.
germayne: Anybody can follow that statement, so I repeat again.
germayne: So basically, right, it means that, oh, you know, if I increase my image quality, the number of parameters scales with the image.
germayne: Anybody wants to tell me how many parameters
germayne: Let's say we assume that there's no buyers.
germayne: How many parameters are there in this block?
Zac Ang: 100.
germayne: No?
germayne: How big is your matrix size?
Zac Ang: Nai.
germayne: No, your matrix is 900.
Zac Ang: Oh.
germayne: Because I didn't draw out. You guys don't mean to draw out, right?
germayne: You have 100 here, you have 9 here.
germayne: my… I have 100 elements on… I have 100 rows, I have 9 columns. Total, I have 900.
germayne: Excluding the buyers.
germayne: So you'll notice this is a very small image, I already need 900 parameters.
germayne: Right, what if I do a 4K image?
germayne: is going to grow, right? So you get to see the idea here is that the number of parameters grow… no, no, I think maybe you guys are tired. But you guys get the idea, right? The number of parameters seems to be growing the image.
germayne: That doesn't make sense, right? Well, how can it be that? You know, my data is small? Oh, I mean, it's not that it's wrong, but you realize that it's not very efficient.
germayne: In this… in this context. So that's actually the motivation for why fit-forward neural network doesn't work that well, because your normal parameter space grows.
germayne: Linearly with the number of pixels.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, now, before we go into how to solve this problem, so the big questions in everybody's head is that we still haven't solved that yet, right? Okay, so I mentioned that the feed-forward neural network actually scales linearly based on the size of the image, right? So, we haven't talked about how to solve it. Now.
germayne: Let's take a step back, again, let's digress again, right? We go back to the original thing that we talked about. So just now, earlier on, for traditional CV, we saw that we can apply some kind of kernel.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: You saw that, right? We can apply some kind of kernel, but now we want to talk a bit about how this kernel is being applied. So basically, this filter.
germayne: Okay, sorry, for the… basically, this is called the filter, but in the neural network, this thing becomes the kernel, but it's the same thing. So essentially, we can apply some kind of matrix, we can apply it on the original image, and the result actually converts the image to some kind of desired feature map. Basically, the output of this is called the feature map.
germayne: Why we call it a feature map is because we are trying to extract something out of it, right? We are actually trying to understand, we are actually trying to convert certain meaning from the image.
germayne: For the edge detector, obviously, you are trying to extract the image out, so the feature map here is actually the edge, the edge of the image.
germayne: So we're going to take a step back. We haven't answered the question previously.
germayne: This one, we haven't answered yet. There's still a very big question mark, okay?
germayne: Yes, straightforward neural network scales linearly scales linearly.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Now, to answer that, we are going to go by… we are going to go back to the traditional computer vision thing, and we are going to understand how this is being applied. So there's this… there's this process.
germayne: Okay, that we'll talk about it later. Okay, we haven't talked about it yet.
germayne: Not yet.
germayne: Okay? The… the… we'll come back to this later, but the idea here is that we… we… we want to give the… oh, wait, sorry. Yes, Philip. Actually, yes.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Sorry, the convolution kernel is applied to every pixel, or to the image?
germayne: Good question, good question. We'll come to that later, we'll come to that later. Yeah, we haven't gone back there yet. So, we will see how this is being applied. But the idea here is that… the idea here is that we want to introduce this mechanism, right? The idea here is that
germayne: Traditional computer vision is saying that, you know, if we apply some kind of filter, which is this guy, right, we apply some kind of property, actually we can get certain kind of output.
germayne: Correct? That's what traditional computer vision is saying, and these filters are predefined by the people that created it.
germayne: Right, you have the Kenny, Gaussian, obviously this, like what I mentioned, this is a Laplacian, based on the Laplacian distribution.
germayne: But the central question here is why not we make the… why not we make the filter some kind of parameter? Why not we make the filter learnable?
germayne: Right, so essentially, instead of a human defining what the future is, right, we make this learnable. So it becomes something that the neural network learns, and the neural network should be the one that decides what to be
germayne: outputted has a feature map, because, like what I mentioned, it's the one that decides what kind of important things that it should be learning, right? So the central gap here is… the central gap here to jump from
germayne: the feed-forward neural network is, instead of flattening everything, why not we make the parameters fixed?
germayne: And you can see the distinction here, right? If I'm making the filter or the kernel.
germayne: this square, learnable. What does this mean? This means that my parameters doesn't grow with the size of the image. Agree with me? Anybody disagree with this statement?
germayne: So, in this case, if my kernel is a 3x3, of course I'm Missing out some details here.
germayne: If the kernel is 3x3, it doesn't matter if my image is 4K, my image is 8K in the future, or if my image is 100K, or if my image is HDM, HD, or if my image is 720p, doesn't matter anymore. Agree?
germayne: So, we are going to move towards that, and that's what makes convolutional neural network very powerful.
germayne: Okay, another… another intuition.
germayne: Okay, so when… when… when human actually looks at the image, right?
germayne: I don't know whether you guys agree with me or not.
germayne: When human being actually looks at the image, right, we actually look at something that is very localized.
germayne: So essentially, when you're a human, right, when you look at an image, you actually see, like, oh, the ears are here, the nose are here, you know, the neck is here, oh, therefore this must be an animal. So, from a human perspective.
germayne: Even though we look at the image as a whole, the details in the image are localized.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: So, I want to repeat this again. So, if you think about it from an image as a whole, right, the details in the image are localized. The years doesn't span across every pixel, right? So what I'm trying to say here is that if you look at the… if you look at this… this image of this very cute animal.
germayne: when you're a human being, you're looking at, okay, what is this thing? This is the eyes, right? So you can see that the eyes is actually localized.
germayne: So what this means is that…
germayne: Actually, somehow we are looking at things in a very localized manner, right? You can see that the nose is here.
germayne: The years is here.
germayne: And because details in the image are localized.
germayne: We are going to create a mechanism in the neural network that looks at things in a very localized manner.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Are you guys able to follow so far?
germayne: Okay, so similarly, if you think about it from the age detection.
germayne: All of these age are actually all very localized.
germayne: Right, these are all very localized areas.
germayne: Can you see, yeah? I'm just drawing. Localize means that I do not need to talk about, I do not need to have access to the entire image all at once in order to make some interesting statement.
germayne: I'm always looking at the details in an individual, localized manner.
germayne: Okay, agree, huh? So far, can follow?
germayne: Anybody here disagree with the statement? Human will… Qin Meng says human will look at… The point in focus.
germayne: Kimeng, you mind explaining?
germayne: What does that mean?
Kim Meng Phoa: As well as something that's similar to your… to what you say is the localized area, because I think using the knowledge of, photography, normally for humans, I will look at those in, those in focus. That means, that of you.
Kim Meng Phoa: It just happened that the depth of use is, the particular straight night is in focus.
germayne: - - okay, well, yeah.
Kim Meng Phoa: So, yeah, because if you look at the photographic point of view, it's… you… once you…
Kim Meng Phoa: That appeal is something like…
Kim Meng Phoa: there's a point of focus between the pre-focus after focus. That means once they're… once they're playing cuts there at certain locations, it will… that location is always in focus.
germayne: Mmm, okay.
Kim Meng Phoa: This image where the… the thing is, the ear, the eye, and the nose is all… is at the… it just happens to be aligned at the… that… that particular plane.
germayne: Yeah,
germayne: Okay, well, I think this is perfect. You are helping me transit to the next slide already. Perfect.
germayne: Perfect, exactly, exactly what I want to… want to… the intuition that I want to give.
germayne: Okay, so with that… with that in mind, right, you guys can start to see why… why this thing is so brilliant. Of course, again, it's by hindsight, right? It works, that's why it's so brilliant.
germayne: So because human beings, right, we always look at it from a very localized manner, you will see that there's this concept called the receptive field. This is actually known as the receptive field.
germayne: The idea here is that later on, right, in the architecture.
germayne: We're going to design it where each of these feature maps, so each of these are feature maps that the model detects. So this is F1, this is F2, and this is F3.
germayne: Okay? I'm sorry, I don't want to confuse you guys, this F is not the function, but this is just different feature map. So the idea here is that, actually, at different passes, and if you guys remember, right, the neural network is like a chain now, it's like a conveyor belt.
germayne: The idea here is that at different layer, the feature map that is learned is actually very different, right? This is your original data set.
germayne: First idea that we want to introduce is that
germayne: everything seems to be localized, so we don't need to… we do not need to create a neural network that looks at every pixel all at once, right? We just need to look at a pixel.
germayne: At a certain localized area, and we should be able to get some information.
germayne: If you notice in the second feature map, the feature map started to become smaller, right? Because the… this is the… of course, for now, you don't know what this is, but you can see that the green area, this is a 3x3
germayne: area of the first localized area, right? Just like a human being, we were looking at the, you know, the animal. Oh, by the way, I do not know what animal that is. If somebody knows, please tell me, in the chat.
germayne: So…
germayne: You can see, right, when we start to see the eyes, the nose, we're actually looking at a certain portion. So the neural network is going to do the same.
germayne: we introduced the whole concept of this filter. The filter is just only going to be a 3x3 filter for now. You see that we're just scanning a certain area, right? We are going to scan everything, and the resulting image is going to be smaller. The feature that's being learned will be smaller, right?
germayne: you notice that by the time it reaches the third, right, you can see that the receptive field actually becomes deeper and deeper. What this means is that the… the… for each pixel in a deeper layer, it's actually projecting on a larger portion of the image.
germayne: So what this means is that, right, interestingly, the neural network, the convolutional neural network, when you learn it, right.
germayne: the deeper the layer, the more abstract it's actually learning. It's actually learning something very abstract about the image.
germayne: Right? Just like a human.
germayne: we first make an inference on what that, you know, what exactly that object is. We look at the eyes, we look at the ears, and then maybe we start to see, you know, whether there's fur, we start to see other parts of it.
germayne: So the idea here is that
germayne: The feature maps, right, as you start to get deeper, the receptive field actually becomes bigger.
germayne: Right? And you can see right here, the receptive field is that this internal layer, this one feature actually talks about a larger, a larger portion. It talks about… it talks about, like, this whole pixel, you know, this rep… this…
germayne: One pixel of this feature map actually can represent certain information about a large pixel.
germayne: Right? So you get… you get this whole idea that, oh yeah, okay, seems like there's this localized manner, and you can't do this with the… you can't do this with the original architecture. You have to use this convolutional method to do that.
germayne: So basically, this is what I'm trying to highlight, right? That…
germayne: Of course, you won't be the one designing the convolutional neural architecture. There's people that created very advanced, complex architecture. So, what I want to mention here is that because of the receptive field, this is a given image.
germayne: after it passes through the first convolutional neural network block, actually it starts to see very basic stuff. And it's actually very interesting, you know, these are actually plotted by visualizing what are the intermediate feature maps. People are actually visualizing it.
germayne: Right? There's actually methods to look at what the model is trying to see. And people actually start to notice that, you know, has the…
germayne: You know, if you're looking at the feature map, inside, right, it's looking at very abstract stuff, man, it looks very scary. I don't really know what it's actually trying to see. But at the… at the start, right, it's just learning by itself that, oh, actually, maybe in order to classify something, let's say in this hypothetical example, whether it's outdoor or indoor.
germayne: From your human perspective, you know that, okay, if I see there's grass, there's trees, must be outdoor. If I see furnitures, must be indoor. But these are all automa- all automatically learned by the model. Nobody is…
germayne: telling the model to do it. You are only giving the model the target labels, and we are only defining the convolutional neural network, the convolutional block, the CB. We call it the CB here, the convolutional block.
germayne: So each of the convolutional blocks, they're actually learning these features. And you see that these are actually… this is exactly the edge detector that we saw. So we don't even need to detect the, you know, we don't even need to define the kernel that detects the edge. The model automatically learns a filter, a kernel, that is able to extract edge, edge.
germayne: And actually deeper, because the receptive field starts to become bigger, it's actually able to learn more and more abstract stuff that helps it
germayne: in determining whether the image has a certain property, whether there's a cat, whether there's a dog, etc, etc. Very interesting, right?
germayne: Alright? Very interesting, right? So these are what people do, and I think what was interesting is people,
germayne: actually, in fact, right, as part of, like, some of the research that I did in my grad studies, you are also able to see where the neural network is actually looking at before they make the decision. So actually, you are able to go very deep into this.
germayne: To interpret how they come to that decision.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So you notice that the, you know, you'll start to notice that in very typical architectures from the ImageNet model, so ImageNet, so, you know, you notice that I'm mentioning this thing called ImageNet for quite some time, right?
germayne: So basically, ImageNet is this bunch of data, I can't remember how many, I think there's 100 classes, a thousand classes. So basically, it's created by this, woman, I think she's called, Li Fei Fei, I think, Li Fei Fei. She's, she used to be a professor at Stanford, and I think she joined Google, and I think she went back to Stanford again.
germayne: So she… I believe she's the one that created ImageNet dataset, and this ImageNet dataset actually created a lot of models that were trained based on this ImageNet dataset.
germayne: And you notice, right, in all of these ImageNet models, right.
germayne: they actually have this very common architecture in the convolutional block, where the resulting features just get smaller and smaller and smaller and smaller. And then they have some… basically, they're just alternating between a convolutional and a ReLU block. They will do a pooling.
germayne: which actually shrinks the resulting data to be smaller. They will alternate again with the same thing, a convolutional block and a nonlinear layer, a ReLU.
germayne: they will do pulling again, you'll repeat this multiple times, and then you'll notice that there's a very common pattern in neural networks. You'll start to see this, right? So this will be the first time that you're seeing it, but you'll start to see that usually the first part, right, this whole portion here.
germayne: This is what we call the encoding process.
germayne: You're basically encoding certain information to certain dimension, right?
germayne: These feature maps, humanly, we cannot see it, but you guys saw that actually we were able to visualize to see that they're actually trying to learn something, right? Like a human being.
germayne: They have their own concept of how to define certain stuff, right?
germayne: we actually call this whole process the encoding process. So you are basically encoding the data to some kind of dimension. So we call this the encoding process.
germayne: Okay? So when people say encode, right, you're basically putting this through some neural network, you're projecting this to some kind of hidden dimension, hidden dimension, HD.
germayne: Okay? And then you'll notice something very similar, is that towards the end, before we make a classification, we will call this a fully connected layer, the FCL.
germayne: I know that if this is the first time that you are seeing this, it's going to be very confusing, but you'll start to see this is a very common template for all of the neural networks, even up till today.
germayne: Okay? I'll repeat again, huh?
germayne: This is an unstructured data, it's an image.
germayne: We are talking about convolutional neural network, a very typical design that people start to do in all of the ImageNet classes model.
germayne: ImageNet, again, is this specific data that people train. I'll talk… it will make sense later on, but for now.
germayne: just imagine that ImageNet is just this open source data that people has, a thousand clusters. People build a lot of models around it.
germayne: You will notice that a common template is they will build these alternating blocks, where each of the feature maps gets smaller and smaller, and the idea here is that
germayne: The model actually begins to learn very abstract representation Of the image.
germayne: And you notice that one characteristic here is that the receptive field actually becomes bigger
germayne: deeper in the layer. One small pixel actually influences a large pixel of the input data.
germayne: Right?
germayne: Very common idea in building neural networks is you want to encode some kind of information. Here, encoding basically means we let the neural network learn. We will let them project the data from the original dimension. Here.
germayne: Typically, we have N by H by W by 3.
germayne: By the end here, you will get something like N, by, K1, K2,
germayne: And then the dimension here can be 500.
germayne: Right, so the dimension now can be projected to be very big.
germayne: And the idea here is that it's a bit similar to doing feature engineering. That's the very hand-wavy way of saying, right? That actually it's learning stuff.
germayne: And it needs higher dimension to represent it.
germayne: But again, this dimension is, you know, it has learned everything, it has learned all the feature map. Now, what you want to do is you want to classify if it's outdoor, indoor, you want to classify if it's a dog or cat.
germayne: you need to do the fully connected layer. So at this point in time, you will flatten everything, and this will repeat what we have learned on Tuesday. Essentially, you see, this FCL, we call it a fully connected layer.
germayne: Usually, this happens at the head of the model.
germayne: Okay? When I say the hit, you know this is at the end. The terminology calls the hit at the end, I don't know why. So when people say that, oh, okay, I will, you know, remove the hit, actually they're talking about the fully connected layer at the end, which is this.
germayne: The fully connected layer here is the same LEGO blocks that you've seen on Tuesday.
germayne: W here, W1, W2, and then this last layer is…
germayne: In ImageNet's case, it's actually a hundred…
germayne: hidden unit, because we want 100 classes, so it needs to output, sorry, it's a thousand classes, so it needs to output 1,000…
germayne: target labels.
germayne: But you notice, right, that this template is actually interesting.
germayne: And what I mean is that most people won't be designing all this neural networks from scratch.
germayne: Right, even for myself, back then, when I did a lot of Kaggle competitions for images, I usually referenced very popular architectures. I don't build them from scratch. And you start to see that there's this pattern of alternating convolutional neural network blocks, and you always need a fully connected layer.
germayne: Understand the intuition?
germayne: I know I'm introducing a lot of stuff, but this is going to be the first time that you see this, but it will not be the last, because this will be the common template for all the
germayne: Modern neural networks.
germayne: Now, I want to ask you guys a question. In this template, what do you think is reusable, and what do you think will be different when we move on to, let's say, NLP, from your intuition? What do you think will be taken out?
germayne: Make a guess.
Zac Ang: The feature learning…
germayne: Exactly. Exactly.
germayne: So, you notice this part will be replaced.
germayne: Right? Why?
germayne: Anybody knows why?
germayne: Because the convolutional neural network is designed in a way to capture the structural data of the image, right?
germayne: Correct? So you notice, right, that in 3.10, when we go to NLP,
germayne: Because the text data is a sequential data, we'll basically replace this entire block. The encoding block will be different.
germayne: So the whole central idea here is that on Tuesday.
germayne: we not just have the fully connected layer, we also actually have the encoding layer. The encoding layer, instead of using convolutional neural network, we were actually putting more W's.
germayne: So, you can imagine right here we can encode with W1, W2, W3, and then usually your final layer is very similar to your fully connected layer.
germayne: Okay? It's just that we encode it differently.
germayne: Alright?
germayne: Okay, so hopefully that gives you the intuition. No math, we're not going to do any more math, but the intuition is as such.
germayne: Okay? So, one last thing to just call out.
germayne: because the data actually get less and less, right? The pixels become smaller and smaller, but the dimension becomes longer. I think you can deliberately see that the image here, 3-channel, then suddenly you can see, the box becomes longer. You guys notice, right?
germayne: You guys can see, right? The width and the height become smaller.
germayne: Because when we go deeper, we don't need very… we don't need a lot of pixels.
germayne: Receptive field is very deep.
germayne: one small pixel can already represent a very big portion of the original image, so the H and W becomes very small now. You can see, it becomes very small, but you notice that the box becomes longer.
germayne: So here is 3.
germayne: here is D1, here is D2, here is D3, here is D4, here is D5. So you notice, the dimension becomes bigger and bigger.
germayne: Right? It's automatically learning more and more features.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So…
germayne: Even though the spatial dimensions become smaller, the model is actually retaining all the information, all the important information.
germayne: Okay, so we no longer need to think about it from a pixel-level perspective.
germayne: Okay, this is also another… this is also another representation, let me see, huh?
germayne: This is also another representation lah. It's actually the same… it's actually the same thing.
germayne: You have a, you have a, you have an image.
germayne: the original image, okay, actually, there's a lot of confusing, confusing images here, but you can see if I cut
germayne: It's actually like that.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, can I, can I ask something?
germayne: Yes, yes, Noelle, yep.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, so, so you, you, the, the previous slide, right, because as, as it passes through the filter,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: it gets longer, and you say it still keeps the information. So it means that…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: No, I mean, intuitively, for me, right, it's like, that small square at the end is also…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's able to keep the… is able to know what's happening before, it's because
Low Keng Teck, Noel: There are a lot of,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Extra information at the other… at the beginning.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That's why, even though you extract
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You go deeper, right, you get lesser information, but you still track… you save… you still keep the
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That means it's also… that means the previous layer, the information is probably a lot of…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: extra information now in front, so I can throw it away. Then, even though I have lesser now, right, I still have a lot. I still know, because…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Before that, a lot of things probably not needed.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yes.
germayne: Yes, yes, yes, I think that that's a good intuition, but I just want to correct some statements that you make, when the model go deeper, right, it's not that the information gets less. The spatial information is less. Spatial as in the pixel. The pixel is smaller. But this dimension, this one, this one is a D, right?
germayne: you just think of it like your features, you think of it like your Visio features, you have initially 76, but when you keep going deeper, right, it becomes more and more. Maybe by here, there's 500.
germayne: Pretty sure.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: What in my spatial, anyway? I take my.
germayne: Spatial, spatial as in the pixel or the pixel form a height. If you look at a picture, there's height and
germayne: there's a height and a width, right? Yeah. You can see that one becomes smaller, the pixel becomes less.
germayne: But the dimension becomes more… Here, your channel only got 3.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, your picture is a 3D picture, you're talking about a 3D picture.
germayne: 2D, 2D, but the data is 3D.
germayne: Wait, Noel, when you look at the picture, your picture's 3D, man? 2D, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yo, it's not a single, you see?
germayne: Cool, but no.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I look at pictures as a picture lah, I don't…
germayne: No, no, no.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the,
germayne: I don't know, but…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Third dimension. So when you say third dimension in the 2D, what does it mean?
germayne: No, no, okay, let me, let me answer. So, when you look at a picture, a picture is 2D, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: But to a computer, a picture needs to store the colors in the.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, 3 colors, right, there's 3 colors, right, yes.
germayne: RGB.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: channels are the emissions video.
germayne: Exactly, exactly. So, the matrix representation of when… if you load it, right, and you look at the matrix, the matrix is three-dimensional, but when you look at it, it's two-dimensional.
germayne: If that.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's not confusing. Yeah, yeah, yeah. But every pixel is actually 3-channel, that's why you have re…
germayne: Exactly, exactly, correct, correct.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, when you say spatial, you're talking about that information…
germayne: Spatial, when I say spatial, it's basically the pixel, the pixel,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: The pixel itself, lah, right?
germayne: Yeah, yeah, the spatial. So the spatial becomes less.
germayne: Spatial, yeah. Make sense? Like, the… the… maybe now H by M becomes smaller, but the dimension becomes longer.
germayne: Okay, and again, again,
germayne: the dimensioning becomes longer, it's not magic, huh? You are the user, the user defines this. You'll start to see later.
germayne: It's a parameter that you define.
germayne: Okay?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Hmm.
germayne: Does that, all good, Noel?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah, so I just wanted to… because…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: picture… I mean, I'm not sure about NLP lah, but picture, I know you have… you know, if you look at it like, I mean, let's say the eye, for example. I mean, I do…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, I do…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: photo touched last time, so it's like… so if I… if I… if I zoom in, right, I see, like, a black color, like, eye… eyeball black, but it's all too… when you zoom in, it's all too black. There are a lot of other grey areas and everything, so…
germayne: -
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So when you start to clean it up, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: or touch up, then you realize that, hey, maybe certain parts, although you remove it, it's still okay, because when you see, you know, you remove it, but when you zoom out, right, it's still okay, you know, you can see it.
germayne: AI.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, I mean, that's my… that's how I… looking at what you are trying to explain here, because…
germayne: Yep, yep, yep. So here, right, here, right, the third dimension is the channel, but when you go deeper, right, it becomes features, really, which is not interpretable by human. So let's say, hypothetically, right here, I put 100.
germayne: Here, the dimension here will become 100 already.
germayne: each hundred, right, you think of it as like a human being. You do your character, right? Each column must represent something. But to you.
germayne: to you, you can, like, oh, I engineer this feature, but to the model now, the model do this 100, right? You cannot interpret it.
germayne: Right? Here, again, let's say it becomes 200.
germayne: He'll become 300.
germayne: Here become 400.
germayne: here become 500. So when we say 500, 400, what is it? We're talking about the features, right? Yeah. The features now becomes a lot, the dimension.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Right? You have your… your N,
germayne: Then you have your… the pixel size lah, right? This one and this one.
germayne: the, the, the, I call it K first lah, K, K1, K2.
germayne: Then you'll hear, right, usually they put a D.
germayne: They call it the dimension. Usually people call it a D. The hidden… it's basically what the model is learning.
germayne: Right, they call it a DLA, right, the dimension lah. So in this case, it's 500.
germayne: Okay? But, you guys get the point, yeah?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But the… but back to the… when we talk about the neural networks like the… at the last lesson, the… the layer is actually determined by the user. I mean, how many years, and how many… that, you know…
germayne: Exactly, yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So in this case, when you talk about 100, like, 0.3 to 100 is actually determined by the user.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because if I look at it, like, the hidden layers and everything, that's what you ask.
germayne: Correct, correct, correct.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah. Because…
germayne: Everything here is customized, nothing here is given to you.
germayne: Your block, you want it to be smaller, you also can do it.
germayne: All I'm just saying is that when people created ImageNet that worked.
germayne: They follow a certain specific formula.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: Got it? Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: and…
germayne: Yes, Philip?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Well, how did they come to a determination that That… that, 500…
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: Features is good enough for that particular.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: We'll be trial and error.
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: objective.
germayne: Good question. That's what people who do research does, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, try arrow.
germayne: Basically, it's a research problem.
germayne: You can also read the… okay, so basically, right, the… usually when they publish the papers, they will share this, but then your natural question will be, like, okay, how people figure out? They just try. I mean, they have certain intuition, they try and see what works.
germayne: And usually people will reference certain other previous published papers, right?
germayne: Correct. So, let's say, for example, somebody released a new language model, is it built from scratch or not? Is the new large language model built from scratch? It's not, right?
germayne: They have referenced somebody's success, and then you just follow.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But I guess the other question is, like, can it be calculated? I think that's what…
germayne: Well, wait, wait, just to be clear, what does that mean, Noel? What do you mean by calculated?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It means, like, it, it's like, like, it's like when you look, when you do the supervised learning, you, you, you, we measure, you talk about having to know the metric first, then you really know what you're looking for. I mean, you work backwards,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So in this case, is it possible to work backwards?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Or you have to, like, try it out.
germayne: No, no, no, no. Neural networks are not… neural networks, the architecture, right, is not solved analytically. It's empirical, which means it's experimental.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: experimental lah. Yeah, empirical means experimental. It means you're trying out, and not do again, and not try, do again.
germayne: Yes, which is why I'm telling you that none of you will be, like.
germayne: Okay, I shouldn't say that, but you… it's not recommended that you create… you create these from scratch.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, he scream.
germayne: You reference, you reference what people has built, you use it, which we'll talk about it later.
germayne: Okay, but I hope everybody gets the G's here, because if you get the Gs here, it'll be very easy moving forward.
germayne: Anybody got any last thing or not? We got a lot of time.
germayne: Yeah, go ahead.
Teng Lee LIM: Okay, last, yes, on Tuesday, right, N is the number of features, right?
germayne: N is the instance, yes. No, no, no, no, no, no. N is the instance.
germayne: When I put airplan apart… Instance is the number of rows, number of sample data you have.
germayne: We call it instance.
germayne: Is that true.
Teng Lee LIM: In this case, n is the number, total number of pixels.
germayne: No, N is the total number of pictures.
Teng Lee LIM: Total number picture.
germayne: Okay, I, I, I, I have you.
germayne: So when you, when you want to train a model, let's say, hypothetically, you want to train
germayne: Let's say, technically, you are very interested in
germayne: predicting docs. You want the model to learn the different type of Dogs or cats.
germayne: You need a lot of training data, correct?
germayne: When you did your Kaggle, you use training data, so how many you need? You need at N.
germayne: the number of images, correct? For each image.
germayne: there will be a size of the pixel. Let's say you use a very small image.
germayne: 300 by 300.
germayne: Okay? So this is the number of pixels, right?
germayne: But because every picture has 3 channels, This is the matrix size.
germayne: Can you see? N comma 300x300 by 3.
germayne: So what does this mean? This means that there's actually n numbers of 300 by 300x3 matrices.
germayne: Agree?
Teng Lee LIM: Hmm.
germayne: Yeah, so does that answer your question? So now, why not ask you, where is your pixel? Where is the pixel?
Teng Lee LIM: Mine's the pixel, I think 300 by 300.
germayne: Exactly, 200 by 200.
Teng Lee LIM: Alright.
germayne: By 3, because 3-channel.
Teng Lee LIM: Yeah.
germayne: G color channel.
Teng Lee LIM: Thank you.
germayne: Gorilla.
Teng Lee LIM: Yes, but the whole thing a bit confusing, but…
germayne: Don't worry, don't worry, I think…
germayne: I think if this is your first time, right, it will be very hard to understand.
germayne: If this is the first time seeing this, it's very hard to understand, because
germayne: I… I cannot, I cannot reset myself now, so to me, right, it's like…
germayne: And you need to play around with it. So, for example, you can go to the 500 row. So, let's say if I go to the 500 row.
germayne: Can somebody tell me what's the size of the matrix? Why not you guys test? Why don't you… I ask you guys.
germayne: So you take the 500th row, I want to take the image at the 500th position. What is my… what is my final matrix sign? Anybody wants to try? Make a guess.
germayne: Here. Let me guess.
Teng Lee LIM: I don't understand your question.
germayne: Okay, so, okay, let me, let me make it, let me make it, okay, let me make it easier, let me, okay, sorry, sorry, let me make it easier.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That's how I understand your question.
germayne: Yeah?
germayne: So, when you train a model, right, you just now tingly asked me about the pixel. So, we already established that the pixel is 300 by 300x3. Let's say I got 10 pictures.
germayne: So my total size is this, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Then touch it, that's it.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's my total, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: I got 10 pictures, mah. Let's say I want to see the 10th… Picture.
germayne: The last one.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: The temperature, lah, not all the.
germayne: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, just one, one picture, one picture.
germayne: Exactly. So then the picture, right, the matrix is like that, 1, 300 by 300 by 3.
germayne: Can follow, right? Because there's only one of it.
germayne: Yeah. So here, right, if you flatten the first dimension, it's the same as 300 by 300x3. You can see that there's nothing, right? 1x300x300x3 is the same as 300 by 300x3.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Kenzie?
germayne: If you cannot see, you just imagine the total elements if you just multiply all of them. So, in this example, I have, well, I have a lot, I have 9… 9… 90K, is it? I have 90K times 3,
germayne: Okay, essentially, I have 90K pixels by 3 channel, right? If I multiply by 1, it's also 90K by 3 channel. So, it's the same, it's the same. So, if I add a 1 here, right?
germayne: It just means one picture. So if I put a 10 here, it means 10 picture lah, right? If I put 100, it means 100 pictures.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Understand, right? Then, you guys saw, you guys saw on Tuesday, sorry, on Tuesday, Soon did the flattening. So he, he basically flattened this. So if you flatten this, right, without removing the information, it's like that, right?
germayne: That's just a total number of elements in that channel. So now, what happens? This becomes two-dimensional.
germayne: Can he see?
germayne: Okay, but my takeaway is go back and practice. This comes with practice, okay? Because I've also been through this process. It's not like… it's not like when I'm born, I know how this works. Agree? So, it took time to get used to it.
germayne: Okay, I'm going to, I'm going to move forward. Okay, anybody got any last questions to ask me?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, so actually, I, I look at last, last, the last lesson's,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Cora. The FC one is where the 28x28
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It's where you flatter the image.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because the size of the.
germayne: Okay, okay, okay, so for, for, okay, so for, for…
germayne: for the Tuesday one, right, there's some new ones.
germayne: Okay, so typically, right, people use this fully connected layer, right, it's because they are encoding, usually they use some other kind of blocks.
germayne: So then they call this the… they call this the… the fully connected layer.
germayne: But then, right, on Tuesday.
germayne: Okay, yeah, let me… let me see if I can open up another visualization, so that it's not too…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, that's why I was saying Tuesday that this 28x3 was very clear, confusing, because the number wasn't very intuitive, like, what it was talking about.
germayne: Okay, so…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But this sample wasn't…
germayne: On Tuesday, right, I… wait, sorry, sorry, shouldn't be using this.
germayne: Too many, too many pen.
germayne: So on Tuesday, right, we just give some basic block, right? We give, like, W1,
germayne: then you put your… your ReLU, W2…
germayne: Sorry.
germayne: How do I remove?
germayne: B1W2 is… W… 3… Peace.
germayne: Beautiful.
germayne: So here's your final one, usually.
germayne: So, in your… in your… in your… in the original one that we teach, right, for the… they call it the feed-forward lah, FF lah, Feed Forward Neural Network.
germayne: Right.
germayne: in here, right, obviously, because everything is built using the same logo blocks, usually people don't go and say that, oh, here is my… here is my fully, fully connected. People don't say that, because actually everything is just alternating this. But if you think about this, like what I mentioned, if you're… okay, let's say, let's say, let's say, I don't want to do the math lah, but let's say here,
germayne: Let's say here, you put a thousand.
germayne: Right?
germayne: But by the time you multiply all the way here, right, your features will be in 1000 already. So, isn't it very similar to the… to the convolutional neural network, where actually here is the feature-generating process?
germayne: You guys get what I'm saying, right?
germayne: Then here, right, usually is the one that we convert the shape back to the number of classes. So if linear regression, we have a Y, blah blah blah blah, whatever.
germayne: So, people don't usually segregate that, but you can see here it's actually also learning, because
germayne: As long as your original data, right, is already projected to a different dimension.
germayne: The model is already building features.
germayne: It's really encoding.
germayne: Right? I mentioned the term encoding, right? So you're basically encoding the data already.
germayne: But people typically don't set a boundary here, because it's actually the same, right? How do I set? Do I call this encoding and call this fully connected? Not really, right?
germayne: The convention is people don't do that, but what you are trying to introduce here to learn the… to train the model is no different than this.
germayne: The only difference, like what I mentioned, is that the template that you start to see is that for this whole portion.
germayne: we start to use certain blocks, right, that works very well for the type of data. In this example, this is a…
germayne: A three-dimensional data, which is an image data.
germayne: But just to tell you guys, right, do you guys remember I mentioned that I did audio detection, I did audio classification, and I also used convolutional neural network?
germayne: Because it doesn't matter, as long as the data input is always represented in Like, a picture, spatially.
germayne: Then, you know, anything that can… the convolutional blocks.
germayne: is perfect for capturing spatial information, because I took so much time to introduce the first part about the idea of localized, right? So if, let's say, your problem, hey, as long as the input
germayne: Actually, it's based on certain patterns on, like, some heat map. I can use convolutional neural network, doesn't have to be all for pictures, people use it for audio as well.
germayne: You guys understand what I mean, right?
germayne: This whole block here, right, works very well because it's trying to capture very local information. Very localized.
germayne: Right? Like, oh, actually, there's some information here. There's some information here. So this works very well. That's why it's encoding its learning.
germayne: Obviously, once it's learning, you need to put it with a fully connected layer, which is what we learned.
germayne: We just don't default.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I can recognize it using it as audio, because a lot of sound, then you just want to hear what the person say.
germayne: No, no, no, no, no. So audio, right, is because the audio is converted to a picture. It's like a picture, right? They call it the male spectrogram.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, correct.
germayne: you can go and look at it. It looks like a picture, basically, it's like a heat map, like…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I see that.
germayne: Like, it's like a lot of colors on it, so… so if you think about it, right.
germayne: the model doesn't know its audio, the model doesn't care, the model just says that, okay, you give me a three-dimension, I just convolute it. Understand?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, but what I'm trying to say is that even if it's audio, right, it's a picture, but we know that in that particular part of that picture, it's actually the important information, because people are stalking. All the rest are just noise. That's why you can track.
germayne: Yeah, you can also think of it that way, lah, intuitively. I think it makes sense lah. Basically, the model will discern whether what is… what is correct or not. You don't have to do that.
germayne: Right.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, if you're, if you're encoding it, you, if at the end of encoding, you see that information of what you have at the beginning, that means that it's tracking, it's throwing away, like, now, yeah, like, you know, it's keeping the important information, but the rest of it, probably not so important, just throw it away, like, noise, right? Just throw away.
germayne: You can think of it that way, lah. You can think of it that way, not wrong, I think. But, yeah, you can think of it that way. I don't think it's a… I don't think it's a wrong way to… to imagine that. The model will determine that lah, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You train a model to track what is noise, what is not.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Then, yeah, yeah, that's what I was thinking of lah, yeah lah.
germayne: Correct, correct. I mean, if you look at this, this is not train lah, right? If you can see this, this is not train. This is not enforced.
germayne: This is trained, naturally.
germayne: To look at this.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But you also, you also, you also will learn, like, what is, like, what is known, what is not, and what to keep, what not to keep, what.
germayne: Yeah, I mean, yeah, it's Yes, yes, yes.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: No, you don't enforce it.
germayne: Yes, I mean, through backpropagation, yes. Okay, but yes, Zach.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, for publication, or… I don't know.
Zac Ang: Mike, just, so the whole feature learning process, if I were to take it to bring it back to last week, so basically what you're saying is that this CNN feature learning process is the hidden layers between the input and the output.
germayne: Exactly, yes, yes, correct. That's a good takeaway, correct. Usually people call it the hidden layer that's learning. Correct, you're right.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah, correct, yeah.
germayne: So the hidden layer, just like what I mentioned, you can put… you can put very big, right? But if you put very big, basically it's learning very complex expression, high tendency to overfeed.
germayne: Right? Your hidden unit typically is the parameter to control what are the features to learn. Exactly, you guys are getting it already, correct? So if you see paper, right, they always talk about it from a dimension, they call it… there's many notations, they can call it dimension, they can call it hidden… hidden… hidden dimension, they can call it hidden units.
germayne: They can call it feature… I mean, it's the same, it's all the same thing.
Zac Ang: So, so the CNN is just one way of deciding how to do the hidden layers.
germayne: Yes, exactly, exactly.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yes.
germayne: the CNN is created for data that is in this format.
germayne: HWC.
germayne: And I already mentioned, does it have to be pictures? No, people have used it for financial data as well. As long as you can… as long as there's some valid reason on why you're doing it.
germayne: Okay, sorry, yeah?
germayne: As long as you have some valid reason.
germayne: and the neural network architecture basically fits your data, then I don't see why not.
germayne: The property here, you notice, right, is I never talk about it from a picture perspective. I'm talking about it from a perspective of what we want to capture. Here, it's capturing very localized information, right? It's capturing localized information, and it happens to work well for image, because image information tends to be localized.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So it's actually very powerful.
germayne: Okay, I think I'll just quickly go through this lah. So, if you were to apply back to your MDs dataset, right, so this is the MDs dataset, the toy data that you guys see, the digits from 0 to 10, I think. 0 to 9, I think, I can't remember.
germayne: So the MNIS dataset is the 28x28x1, because there's no color, right? So essentially, here you can see that the… the… the very common
germayne: architecture that people do is they alternate, they first do a convolutional, and you can see suddenly the feature becomes a lot. You start to grow the feature, right? Then you do a max pooling. So usually, usually a pooling is like a way to reduce the dimension, reduce the spatial dimension. This one reduce the spatial, doesn't reduce the dimension.
germayne: Sorry.
germayne: Your, your, your data has a… has a…
germayne: The spatial dimension, basically this one.
germayne: The pooling, right, basically aggregates it to make it smaller.
germayne: But the dimension here, right, the hidden unit, right? The hidden dimension, the feature map, it doesn't reduce that. So basically, people will alternate with the pooling, then you do another convolution, then you do the… that's why you see the square becomes smaller and smaller, it's because of the pooling, right? They have different pooling, you have average pooling, you have max pooling, but the whole idea here is that pooling basically performs
germayne: one level of dimension reduction, which is basically here, right? Because the idea is that maybe I don't need all the pixels. Maybe all I need is that maybe the model will have learned that maybe a certain area that's very bright, right? I just take that, and I should be able to have enough information for that spatial location, which is this square.
germayne: Right? But, of course, I retain all the dimensions, because each dimension here can be a feature that is learning. Maybe one of the features here is the edge. This one is looking at something else. So basically, it's all looking at different things from the dimension perspective.
germayne: Okay, so this is exactly the same thing.
germayne: Then again, you see at the end here, right.
germayne: this one, right, is the same template that we did. Basically, the formula is you have your feature F,
germayne: Okay, I call it F, so F is basically the output from here.
germayne: Right?
germayne: The F will be flattened.
germayne: And what you'll do is you'll take the same… the same multiplication again, you'll take… pass through a hidden layer.
germayne: So basically, you do this, right? So you use F now, because F is the final output that has… contains all the features about the image.
germayne: Okay, so we'll talk a bit about the way to do the convolutional, we'll do the convolutional mechanism. So just now there was a question, right?
germayne: actually, how does convolutional… how does performing the operation of convol… performing this convolutional operator, how do we actually do it? So the idea here is that, right, now.
germayne: Instead of defining the kernel, the kernel becomes the parameters, okay?
germayne: So you have a few parameters that you can decide. First, you have to decide the kernel size. You can decide the kernel size. You can also decide how many kernels are there, right? That determines the dimension.
germayne: So the idea here is that if you have different kernel, each kernel will learn a different thing, right? And if, let's say, I put 100, it's very similar to your hidden unit. Then there will be 100 kernels extracting 100 different items.
germayne: And each kernel, the widths are the parameters, okay? So basically, these will be applied to the image patch. Now, why do I talk about time series? It's because…
germayne: If you guys remember, in time series, we talk about
germayne: I mentioned this, I mentioned to you guys, right, that let's say, for example, you do a lot of stocks technical analysis.
germayne: what do you do to smoothen the… the two-dimensional string? What do you guys do?
germayne: Who remembers?
Zac Ang: average.
germayne: What's the, what's the, what's the exactum called?
Zac Ang: Moving a boot.
germayne: We talk about the moving average, right? So if you think about moving average, what did we do?
germayne: We put a square here, and then we move the square across the data, right?
germayne: And each of the squares, what are we doing? We are just aggregating them.
germayne: Correct? We just take the average, and then… and then what we say is that the square is usually 2K plus 1, it's odd.
germayne: Because we want to put the center Correct?
germayne: Right, we talked about this, right? So you took this. So now the same thing for convolution is that this is just 2D, this just becomes 2D.
germayne: So, I have a picture.
germayne: I have a… I have a pixel.
germayne: So how do I do the convolution?
germayne: I do the same thing. Okay, this is a bad example, but it's supposed to be odd, but…
germayne: Same thing, right? It needs to… it tends to be odd, but this is just a bad example, this is a bad example, by the way, but I'm just trying to show. So how you do it? You're doing the same thing as the moving average.
germayne: You take here, you apply the weighted aggregation, right, because each of the pixels has a weight. Here, obviously, the weight is just 11111.
germayne: Right, so if, let's say, my… my moving average, right, is… I'm doing an… I'm doing an average of 5 elements, my window size is 5, I'm just taking each of them weighted equally, right? I take this one, plus this one, plus this one, plus this one, plus this one, divided by 5. So you notice the weight is 1.
germayne: But here, right, the width cannot be 1, the width can be more than 1, so the width is actually learned by the model. So what you're doing is you take the pixel at this spot, you multiply by the position of the kernel here, so if, let's say, the kernel here is 5, the pixel here is 6, then here will be 30.
germayne: Plus, you take the width at this spot, multiply by the pixel, you get a second value, you take this.
germayne: And you take these, and then you just aggregate them.
germayne: So basically, that's what the convolution is doing.
germayne: Correct? Now, similar to what we do for this, you need to scan this, right?
germayne: So after it's done, after it's done on this, what do you guys think will be next?
germayne: So after it's done calculating this, what do you think will happen?
germayne: We just shifted, right?
germayne: So the next color basically looks like that, so it just shifts by one.
germayne: So once it's done, right, where do you go? You shift it again.
germayne: You guys get the idea lah, right? So, very sim… exactly the same as this. Just that this one, you do 2D across the line for convolutional or cross-covaluation, it's the same process.
germayne: Basically, you're just… you're just moving the sliding window of the kernel, and this is the square,
germayne: This square contains certain kind of weights.
germayne: So, I'll just put it as P1, P2… Petrie, P4.
germayne: So, you can think about this, right? The width here that is learnable by the kernel, actually, you can think of it like what Noel is saying. Okay, so I think, Noel, what you said is correct. Maybe the model just learns that maybe every pixel at the top right-hand side is useless, so it will just be 0. It can be a zero here, so it will just automatically delete away.
germayne: You guys get what I'm saying?
germayne: So the weights here are learned, and then you are just basically sliding this across the image here.
germayne: And we're just aggregating the pixels into a smaller… so there'll be a smaller resulting…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Picture here. Yeah, so…
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: But pitot cannot be forever 0, right?
germayne: Michonne?
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: your… you just somewhat mentioned, like, if, let's say, P2 is…
Phillip Tan Lip Teck: equivalent to zero, because maybe it's nonsense, that's why it's suppressed. But you're using these same metrics across.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, correct, correct. I'm just giving an example lah, I'm just giving an example, yes, but you're right. The right, you're very right that this is also the very important point. You are very right that this kernel that we are learning, right, is now being applied on every image.
germayne: So it will be updated by everyone, correct? So I'm just giving an example where the intuition here is that this will actually influence what is extracted out of this.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: You guys saw that if you apply the Kenny operator, you can actually get the edge. So basically, right, this thing can influence what is getting… what is extracted out of the image.
germayne: is being learned. I'm just giving an example that, hypothetically.
germayne: it learns about a certain property, maybe it will try to delete, I don't know. It's just an example, but you're right that… and again, right, if you relate this back to the original statement, why don't we just use fit-forward? You notice that this doesn't scale with the size of the picture, right?
germayne: I decide the fixed kernel, That's the fixed number of parameters.
germayne: Now, what's my parameter? Again, right, this is a very bad example, because the size usually needs to be odd. Same reasons why your moving average is 2K plus 1.
germayne: Okay? It's usually not… because you need to know where to put it, the center.
germayne: So it's usually in odd number.
germayne: Here, right, in this example, let's say it's a… just a hypothetical example, this is one kernel. One kernel.
germayne: So, if you look at this, right, I use one kernel of weights, I perform a convolutional operation, I get one feature. This is one feature, right?
germayne: Can see, right? So, what does this mean? If I want 100 feature.
germayne: I just have 100 kernela, right?
germayne: So the number of kernel basically tells me, well, the number of features I want to extract out.
germayne: So, if you think about it, right, at the very end, let's say your image is N by…
germayne: H by W by 3.
germayne: Right? Hypothetically, you can get N by H… at the N, if let's say I got 100 kernel.
germayne: I have 100 features.
germayne: Right? So the model is actually learning what to take out.
germayne: We're basically learning 100 extraction.
germayne: This is exactly the same as on Tuesday, when I say that if I take W, multiply by D, suddenly I become N by 100.
germayne: Isn't it the same? It's the same, right? Basically, this thing is actually learning some kind of projection to project it to something that is useful.
germayne: So that's what I'm trying to say.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, essentially, you can see this is the thing, and then it ends up learning all the feature maps.
germayne: Right? So you can see, the illustration here is just showing… okay, again, this is a bad example lah, okay? It's supposed to be… it's supposed to be odd. But again, here, in this hypothetical example, it's a 2x2… oops, sorry. It's a 2x2 kernel.
germayne: Okay? And what we do is we just pass the 2x2 kernel, we start here.
germayne: We start here.
germayne: We start here, and then we are actually shifting like that.
germayne: Can see, huh? I'm doing… I can… I can see I'm moving the square, right?
germayne: So when it moves, right, obviously you start to notice that actually the resulting picture will always be smaller lah, correct? Because I'm actually removing information. So this is the resulting feature map.
germayne: And this is for one kernel. The second kernel will do the same thing, the second kernel will also do the operation. So, each kernel will have a different feature map, okay?
germayne: And that explains the feature, why the feature actually relates to the number of dimensions. You can see here, this is the number of dimension.
germayne: So, this picture becomes a smaller one, then usually what people do is they do the pooling. So, you can see right here, we do the pooling. The max pooling basically just say that
germayne: Again, we, we pass a, we pass a, we pass a kernel.
germayne: And then for each kernel, we just take, like, the max, or we take the average.
germayne: So basically, we aggregate, we make them smaller again.
germayne: Right? By taking things that we need.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So yeah, so basically, basically that's it.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Actually, probably a better word is generalize, like… Which one? I mean, you take, let's say, you take average, but the main thing is to actually generalize.
germayne: It's a parameter, it depends. Whether you take mean, max.
germayne: That one, I think it depends. If that's your question, that one is a…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, yeah, maybe that's not my question. I was saying that the intuition is to generalize it so that you don't… yeah.
germayne: Correct, lah, correct. So it also tries to take in… it also tries to learn that, actually, I don't need all the pixelma, right? Maybe… Yeah. Maybe if some area is very bright, I can… I can say something about it already.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, I'm just going to skip this lah, but in practice, the kernel is supposed to be odd lah. And you guys know because I relate this back to the… I relate this back to the time series. It needs to be odd. Now, you guys realize that just now, right, I mentioned that I move it one by one, right? You can move this, right? I mean, I mentioned something like that. So I only move it, like.
germayne: Like, like, like, like, like that, like that. I move it like that. So that's what we call the strike.
germayne: You can make the strike to be 2, so 2 means it moves by 2 pixels. You can see, so here, number 1, then it moves by 2. So this strike, right, determines the final outcome as well. The strike also determines the size of the output.
germayne: Stripe equals to 3, basically, you see, see that the next move, right, is by 3 pixel.
germayne: So I only moved 4 times.
germayne: So, obviously, you can see the strike is also a parameter that you choose, where it decides the feature. If you want, like, to fully scan everything, right, then your stride is smaller. But if you choose very big stripe, right, basically, it's like, well, you know, it's really completely localized?
germayne: Right? You can see, right, I'm not caring about the overlapping information here, I just straight away move to the next.
germayne: So the strike also influences the resulting feature maps that is being extracted, which is also another parameter.
germayne: So now you guys start to realize that the more powerful the algo is, right, the more decisions, the more knobs you need to decide.
germayne: Which is why you don't typically build one from scratch. You try to follow what somebody has already built.
Josiah Ho: Jermaine, sorry, does that also mean that with a bigger stripe, you get lesser details?
germayne: With a bigger strike, your feature maps get smaller.
germayne: So, you will see that there's a formula later to calculate, based on your stripe, based on the kernel size, what's the resulting size of the feature map, yes. But you can see, right, the number of output here is less, mah. 1, 2, 3, 4, done already, I only got 4.
germayne: If I do strike equals to 3, I only got 4 pixels. But if I do more strike, I might have more resulting pixel, correct?
germayne: So your feature maps become smaller.
germayne: Oh, yes, yes, Lanson?
Lim Hung (Lanson): So, actually, is it right to say that after the first contribution.
Lim Hung (Lanson): Then we are not talking about pixels anymore.
germayne: After the first convolution, we are not…
Lim Hung (Lanson): We're not talking about pixels anymore. There's no more pixels because of.
germayne: I think you can… you can… you can say that, like, it becomes an aggregate of pixels, really, actually.
Lim Hung (Lanson): Yeah, it's not upset anymore, right? It's like, maybe shapes instead, or lines instead of ready, right?
germayne: Correct, correct. So, I think it has already not been… the… the data has already been aggregated, lah, you can think of it that way. Yeah. And it's trying to extract stuff. So basically, right, if you look at this, right.
germayne: A filter actually can transform the output of the image.
germayne: So, at the… after the first convolution, right, the resulting image just becomes what the feature is trying to extract out. It's no longer the original pixel. I mean, it's pixel in… it's still image, but it's no longer human… what human perceives. It's just what the filter is trying to extract. That's what it's trying to say. Does that make sense, Lanson?
Lim Hung (Lanson): Yeah, lots of, I mean, I think it makes more sense once I start looking at it as an image anymore. After the first convolution, it's no longer an image, no matter blurry, or less detail, all those are not correct, right? There's no… there's no image to stick off anymore.
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. You can think of it that way, lah, you can think of it that way.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I tend to think of it as, like.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Image from the computer's, vision perspective, rather than the human's perspective.
germayne: It's just Matrix right? It's just a.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I mean, I mean, to the computer, this is image to them,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because it's what they see, but it's not… it's not meant for us to see, yeah, so…
germayne: But there are, of course, there are methods to go and reverse engineer and try to guess what they're saying lah, but you are right, you are right that…
germayne: Usually when they project, right, usually when we encode something, it's not meant for a human to understand.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: I mean, I put it, like, in a very hand-wavy manner, but… Okay, so one thing just to describe, right, that we have the size of the kernel, K1, K2,
germayne: Which is a parameter you set?
germayne: You also have the stride, which is what you said, and then finally, you can also set the padding. So why do you want to set the padding? It's because if you look here, right.
germayne: You might want a case where you don't want the… you don't want the pixel to suddenly become… you don't want the output
germayne: Feature map to change.
germayne: Because if you do a convolutional operation, so if you look at this, right, the kernel and the convolutional property, or later I'll talk about why I keep talking about this cross-correlation and convolution, but
germayne: from a… from this standpoint, if I apply this thing right here.
germayne: you can see that if I don't apply padding, basically the resulting feature map will be smaller. So actually, I can apply a pad.
germayne: So the padding basically just means that you pad the data to be… so this is the original pixel, right? You can pad the data here, and there are many, many padding mechanisms. You can pad with zero, you can pad with reflection.
germayne: So basically, the idea here is you just pad some additional buffer, right? Usually, it's, so here, the padding is one, so one on top, one below. And if you do this padding, right, you do the convolution, basically, you'll get the same size back.
germayne: You guys can see lah, right? Because if you don't do padding, right, the feature map will be small, so because your convolutional start here, mah.
germayne: That's you.
germayne: Right? But if you do padding.
germayne: Your padding starts here. So the overall final convolution, right, will be… you'll get the same size. So you'll see there's actually a formula to calculate lah.
germayne: And sometimes you need the formula, it's because you need to track, when you write the code, right, in PyTorch, sometimes you need to track the output size, so that you need to make sure that the in-channel and out-channel is relevant.
germayne: Okay, so this is the padding. So this is also another parameter that you can decide.
germayne: Now, again, pooling is the thing that I have already mentioned. It's a form of dimension reduction, because
germayne: It could be that when you put max pooling, the model just falls to know that, okay, maybe I just learned that.
germayne: taking the maximum… taking the… taking the maximum, right, is actually important, right? So, it really helps in not relying a lot. The hand-wavy intuition here is that you just don't want to rely too much on certain specific pixel, or a specific position, so you just take the pooling.
germayne: So you take an aggregated view of the spatial information, rather than looking at a specific pixel, okay? So that's the reason for why you want to introduce pooling. So you can see that here it also reduces the representation spatially, right, and the overall number of parameters.
germayne: Right? And you don't want to cause any reliance on a specific area or feature, so you take an average. Because you don't want the model to learn that, well, maybe top right-hand corner, you know, if it's like that, if it's like this number, then it will be, like, this certain property. You take max, or you take average. Okay, so you force the model to distribute
germayne: The information, especially.
germayne: Okay, this one, I think you guys can go back, but basically, this is just a formula. You can just take this formula, and you can see the formula is a function of the stride.
germayne: the strike size.
germayne: is the formula of the padding, right? The padding… the reason 2P… anybody wants to tell me why is it 2P here?
germayne: Why must I take 2 times P? So if I set padding to be 1,
germayne: Why is my… why my… why is this a 2?
Teng Lee LIM: Nothing, like… Not funnily.
germayne: Okay, correct. So left and right, top and bottom. So for this pixel, right, if I add padding 1, I'm going to add 1 here, and one here. So you notice, from the height perspective, it's plus 2.
germayne: You can see, right? H prime is equal to H plus 2.
germayne: Can't see?
germayne: So, padding size 1 means you take 2P here. But the point here is that this just tells you what is the final size of the image lah, after you apply the convolutional stripe.
germayne: So this is just the formula, I think it's quite useful.
germayne: Okay, so, again, right, most of the application of CNN is that
germayne: it is often used for image classification. If you want to predict whether the image has a cat, the image has a dog, fantastic, right? Oh, by the way, I'm just curious, anybody watch a… anybody watch a sitcom that is known as Silicon Valley?
germayne: Has anybody watched Silicon Valley before?
germayne: Oh, no onea.
germayne: Out of, like, 44… or 43… oh, okay, so Gwen watched it.
germayne: Yeah, so you can… you wanna use it to predict hot dog or not, you can use it, right? So basically, you guys aren't… if you guys know the joke.
germayne: So, so, image classification, object detection, we talk about it. There are, of course, some differences in object detection. They have a different, there's a different…
germayne: I think a convolutional operation, right, they also have a difference in architecture, and of course, they also need to handle the bounding box, so obviously that we are not talking about it today, but a lot of this component is still similar.
germayne: Okay, so you can see… This is actually everywhere.
germayne: Okay, so I'll pause here first. Anybody has any questions for me?
germayne: Maybe I think we can take a break after this. Anybody got any last question?
germayne: If not, let's take a break. We come back at 8.55.
germayne: Okay, I hope you guys had a good water break.
germayne: BioBrick.
germayne: Are you guys back?
germayne: Okay, not sure whether I can fulfill Kim Meng's, request to end early. I didn't know it took so long.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, let's start, let's just, let's, let's continue. Okay.
germayne: So we are at the last segment, I think. Last few segments lah. I'll go a bit faster.
germayne: So…
germayne: we learned about the convolutional neural network already. Actually, you guys are already equipped with it. The next step is just to learn how to apply it from the code perspective. But for this section, we're just going to talk a bit about training optimization, okay? Just a quick one. So typically, right, for computer vision tasks.
germayne: it is very common to have something called data augmentation. So basically, what you do is, you can basically add some kind of noise to the data, so that the model can be very robust to learn, to learn. So what people usually do is, these are some of the very common operations you can do, horizontal, vertical, flip, 45,
germayne: you know, rotation, you can blur a bit, you can add some noise, you can make it darker. The idea for this is because, in reality, the image itself, the quality might not be good. So what you can do is you can do data augmentation for the computer vision task.
germayne: What this means, right, the takeaway, right, is that actually this is a very easy thing, not much takeaway for you guys, but the idea here is that usually this is all handled by the trainloader. I think you guys have saw that Sun has talked about the trainloader. So for image, right, what happens is that typically you don't load all the image into memory at once, because the image data is very big.
germayne: So, image is actually usually low in training time.
germayne: And you apply the data augmentation only during training. So obviously, you only apply this during training. During inference, you don't apply this. Why would you pollute the inference data? So this is only applied during training. The trainloader will handle this.
germayne: Okay? And one more takeaway is that this, usually for computer vision tasks, we no longer follow the one epoch, the one epoch.
germayne: slash iteration concept.
germayne: The reason for this is because…
germayne: I want you guys to just have this takeaway, right, is that when you do data augmentation, it just means that our dataset actually grows.
germayne: You can see our one image here.
germayne: I can randomly rotate any rotation. So one image, I can actually generate many datasets. Agree, right? Because the number of augmentations that I can do is, well, a lot.
germayne: So what this means is that in training time, I can literally define my iteration to be any number, it doesn't have to be bounded by the training data. You guys previously learned on Tuesday that I mentioned that one epoch basically means the full iteration, right? Full iteration means the total number of your data set, and
germayne: divided by batch size B. That's your number of iterations. But that will not hold for computer vision tasks when you do data augmentation, because I can essentially do unlimited number of iterations, right? I can do, like, well, I can… you're the one that defines it.
germayne: So, very, very powerful for computer vision, usually data set not a problem.
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Just talk a bit about some extra stuff.
germayne: So, of course, there are a lot of, research on… a lot of data augmentation, so these are some of the things that I did during my grad studies.
germayne: So, essentially, you can apply, there are a lot of augmentation, so this is the basic augmentation that's done. So, again, you can see it's the doc, dog, and cats.
germayne: basically pets, pet data. Then there's also, like, other kind of…
germayne: augmentation that you can do, they call it the cut, mix, and the mix-up. I'm not sure whether now, this is actually, like, many years back. So, cut, mix, and mix up, basically, you see I'm actually augmenting my data by merging data within the batch. Not sure if you guys can see, you can see, right, the data looks very weird.
germayne: Right? So basically, what you're trying to do is you're actually creating arbitrary data, right? Very noisy data that are created based on the blend of the internal data. So you can see, right, what I'm trying to tell you is that for data augmentation, potential is endless. You can generate a lot of data, and typically, empirically, it helps in training.
germayne: Okay, another thing to just talk about is the normalization. So, we didn't really talk about it.
germayne: But I just want to emphasize that it's a very normal practice for people to do normalization.
germayne: Before they put the data into neural networks, okay?
germayne: But of course.
germayne: people also introduce what is called a batch normalization. So you can either do a preprocess step where you normalize your data, this is basically the standard scaling that we did, right? The standardization using the mean and variance, right? And the reason for this is because yesterday I emphasized a lot about the gradient flow.
germayne: We did the back propagation, you guys saw that, okay, the gradient from upstream is always passed downstream.
germayne: Right? And the idea here is that you don't want your gradient flow to be very small. You guys saw yesterday, right, the gradient flow very small, people in front benefit, but people at the back doesn't benefit, and…
germayne: End of the day is teamwork. If the weights at the back is nonsense, the model is just gonna be shit.
germayne: So, usually the normalization methodology is you want to improve the gradient flow, and that actually helps the model to learn more effectively.
germayne: Another concept to think about it is that the overall cost function, right, the loss function with respect to your parameters, it will actually be more symmetrical, rather than more elongated.
germayne: So this actually links back to the gradient descent portion. So long story short, normalization is great, right? So what exactly is batch normalization?
germayne: Bash normalization, right, is actually another LEGO block that you can put inside your neural network. So rather than you do the normalization
germayne: at the start.
germayne: you can actually define the normalization within your weight. So basically, after you do your weights, you do batch normalization, then you do your ReLU.
germayne: Okay? So usually people put it before the… in practice, at least on the paper, people put it before the activation function. Whether it works or not, you have to try it empirically. But the idea here is that very big values, again.
germayne: When you are talking about certain nonlinear functions, very big values get saturated.
germayne: So what you want is that you want to make sure that the values is small, so that the gradient
germayne: doesn't… becomes very unstable, and therefore it can be passed backwards, okay? If the gradient is saturated, basically you are passing nothing back. We are just passing 0, which means that all the W's at the back cannot be updated, right? Again, equation W equal to W minus alpha.
germayne: Alpha?
germayne: DL over DW.
germayne: Right? This one is calculated
germayne: Right? Using some portion of the upstream data. So if the upstream gradient is very low, this will be very small. If this is very small, your W is not changing. If W is not changing, basically not learning anything, okay?
germayne: So batch normalization is just another label block you can put, and the beauty about batch normalization is that it's actually learning there's a parameter. The idea here is that it will actually learn when to normalize and when not to normalize, okay? So there's actually a parameter for batch normalization.
germayne: Okay, you can see this is basically what I mentioned. This is basically the loss function with respect to the parameters.
germayne: if you do not have the normalization in place, it might be elongated, which means that it's not symmetrical, right? So you want the laws to be very symmetrical, so that the learning is stable. A vanishing gradient is basically the property that I talk about, right? You can see that
germayne: For sigmoid, You can see that, this is… this is the sigmoid function.
germayne: You can see that for the derivative, right, if you were to differentiate sigmoid, the derivative looks like that.
germayne: So what this means is that the gradient at the extreme values are very small, right? So you don't want the values to be very big, otherwise the gradient cannot… cannot… cannot… cannot…
germayne: Flow backwards during backpropagation phase, phase.
germayne: Okay? This one you'll read yourself.
germayne: Okay, then the last thing, right, is that actually for neural network, there is actually two types of regularization, okay? If you use PyTorch, actually, it has this thing called L2,
germayne: Nom.
germayne: Or the L2 regularization.
germayne: Anybody remember what this L2 does? When did we talk about this L2?
Zac Ang: regression.
germayne: Regression, exactly. We talked about reach regression, right? Reach regression, I mentioned that L2 basically shrinks the weight.
germayne: So if you go into PyTorch, right, you'll find that the documentation will be just called weight decay. So basically, L2 can also be used to regularize, but here we are not talking about the L2 norm, right? We are talking about something else. So that is a separate way to regularize the weight. Basically, you can shrink the weight.
germayne: Here, this is another thing called dropout. So basically, in your LEGO blocks, you can also add a dropout layer. So what the dropout does is that the intuition is that during learning.
germayne: what it will do is that it will randomly deactivate with some kind of probability, it will set the probability between 0 and 1, right? Again, it's another parameter that we are setting.
germayne: So actually, at this point in time, you guys realize that there's so many parameters in neural network, agree, right? I mentioned that it's very powerful, but a lot of things.
germayne: So, very unlikely that you will create something that's very good if it's the first time that you are writing a neural network, so it's very hard. But anyways, for dropout, how it works is that you are actually setting a probability for the LEGO block itself, so for that block, right, for that linear block, W1,
germayne: Essentially, inside, you have the… you have… let's say you have H number of hidden units. Let's say you set H to be 100.
germayne: What you can set is you can set the dropout probability to be P between 0, 0, and 1. What does dropout means? Dropout basically means that if you set the probability to be 0.5, it means that randomly, 0.5 of the time, it will deactivate one of the hidden units.
germayne: So let's say, for example, during training, during backpropagation.
germayne: These will not be updated, this will be deactivated.
germayne: These will not be used.
germayne: Right? What is the intuition of doing this? The intuition of doing this is so that you don't want to overfeed. You want to… you want to… you don't want the model to keep relying on one of the hidden units. So if this hidden unit is deactivated, the training will now focus on using this.
germayne: others, right? And then during the next iteration, during training.
germayne: this one might be deactivated. So everything will be at 50% probability to be deactivated. So maybe one of the runs, hey, maybe this is deactivated. So now the model needs to rely on this.
germayne: So what this means is that the model will realize that I cannot rely on this 2% too much, right?
germayne: this 3% too much, so maybe I will now focus on this.
germayne: Because if the model ends up relying on one of the hidden units too much.
germayne: This hidden unit might learn specific properties, and it might be overfitting, because maybe it might not generalize the… it might not generalize to the other data set.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So obviously, if you'll drop out too high, right, basically nothing is learning. That's what it's trying to say.
germayne: Now, I want to ask you guys a question. Do you guys think that dropout is activated during inference?
germayne: Let's say today you are ready to submit to Kaggle. Do you activate dropout?
Zac Ang: No.
germayne: Zach, why? Why do you think it's no?
Zac Ang: The model already learned it what?
germayne: Okay, very simple answer. Any, anybody else?
germayne: Anybody else want to think about it? So, I mentioned that dropout will, at a P probability, deactivate during training. So then, do I activate this during inference? Let's say if I want to submit to Kaggle, to Leaderboard, do I activate it?
germayne: Come give a try. Someone else, give a try.
germayne: What do you guys think?
germayne: Come on, if you guys need to leave early, you guys need to participate.
germayne: We are wasting precious time.
germayne: Come on, someone else except Zach. What do you guys think? Anybody, anybody has any opinion? What else?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I think you probably don't turn it on, so…
germayne: Daniel, what's your thought process?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Of course, it's like,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Of course, during training, you don't turn it on, it's to prevent overfitting. Then, if you turn it on during production, wouldn't it be overfitting as well?
germayne: Okay, so, I'll give the answer. No, also, you got it correct.
germayne: But it's not because it overfits during production, it's because you want your best performance, right? Why would you randomly turn it off during production, correct?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You know, you know, because your training is that we are… unless you're training…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Got something special, lah, I don't know, I'm not sure.
germayne: Okay, although, although in Kaggle, there are people that still choose to use dropout, but I think that's a topic for another day. Okay, but in production, you don't activate the dropout, okay?
germayne: Okay, so I think… I think, I think that's all. So I will now hand over to Soon to do the exercise, then if we have time for maybe soon, if it's possible, to give me 5 minutes at the end, then I'll go through the last part.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: But, yeah, I'll hand over to Sun.
Soon | NTU: Chimei, you need only 5 minutes for the transfer learning.
germayne: Oh, no, no, sorry, sorry, sorry. Actually, there's transfer learning. You have a segment on transfer learning, right?
Soon | NTU: Yo.
germayne: Okay, okay, then you do your.
Soon | NTU: Should we continue with all the slides? Then I will do the quote on, holistically on Saturday.
Soon | NTU: Other than how…
germayne: Also can, also Ken, also Ken, yeah, also Ken.
Soon | NTU: So then, you don't have to, like, rush.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
germayne: Okay, good idea. Anybody, object?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: No.
germayne: Okay? No object, because I think everybody just wants to go back.
Soon | NTU: Everybody…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: And also, because you teach so much things, now you break, then come back again, then… Get lost again.
germayne: Okay, good.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: There'll be another thing, another load of…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: informational, I think we are not CNN, unfortunately, so…
germayne: Okay.
germayne: Okay, so.
Edwin Yap: I don't think we can end it then,
germayne: No, we can, we can. If, let's say, we don't do the… we don't do the exercise, I think it's possible. But, yeah.
germayne: Okay, I… I… okay, so just let me transfer, let me continue.
germayne: Okay, so the last part, right, for CNN, right, is transfer learning, and the idea for transfer learning is that
germayne: transfer learning is actually not just for CNN, right, but it's a very applicable
germayne: concept that's usually taught in CNN, because it works for CNN. But the whole idea is that you guys realize so far, up till this point, right, that actually when we are updating our model.
germayne: Right? We are only using Gradient descent, applied to our weights, Oh, wait, sorry, I'll…
germayne: I hate using the… this weight.
germayne: So you guys realize, right, that for your weights, right, you guys are actually updating using gradient descent.
germayne: And then, of course, there's the… there's the bias, which I never talk about it.
germayne: But it's essentially the same.
germayne: Right? You notice that we are just updating this, so what this means is that actually, in theory, the weights can always be updated from something else. So, what this means is that if the model is actually trained
germayne: to perform certain tasks, you can actually make use of what people has already done, conceptually, correct? So that's a very key difference of neural networks as compared to other models, because conceptually, I'm just updating the weights, which means that if you give me a weight, I can always use it, right? It might not necessarily be useless for another separate task.
germayne: So the idea here is that, actually, ImageNet, right, people train a lot of models for ImageNet, and they realized that actually, even though the model was not trained on their task.
germayne: It can actually be used as a starting point to update the model, you don't have to train from scratch.
germayne: Okay? So, intuitively, it makes sense, right? Like, even for the example that I showed, you want to predict cats and dogs.
germayne: For example.
germayne: Your initial base model might not need to be trained on animals, it can be trained on general purpose tasks, because anyway, the model do learn something useful, correct? But you might want to start using transfer learning in order to start from this model that was trained, rather than to re-update your weights from scratch.
germayne: Because I remember that… remember I told you that usually your weights are initialized, there's some form of initialization, we're not talking about it.
germayne: But you initialize your weights with some kind of initialization. These weights are random nonsense initialization. It's not learning anything. So the idea is that it's better for me to use something that has been pre-trained already. That's what we call pre-trained model. So now you guys start to understand the term, right? Pre-trained model.
germayne: And you start to see that actually a lot of people are also applying these for large language models, right? Somebody has already pre-trained, somebody has already performed
germayne: Certain pre-training, you're just only doing fine-tuning.
germayne: Okay, and that is a term that people use for transfer learning.
germayne: Now, back to the… back to the original, original, thing that we talked about. I mentioned that for ImageNet models, they actually train it on a thousand classes, right? Fefei Li actually, you know, started this ImageNet dataset, and then people created all the ImageNet models.
germayne: I mentioned that this whole part is about doing the feature map.
germayne: This is called the fully connected layer.
germayne: Right.
germayne: What happens is that, because this is a classification task, right, the final layer is actually a block that has a thousand.
germayne: by the input from the previous block, so this is the in layer.
germayne: Right? So essentially, if you think about it.
germayne: Does everybody need the 1000 class? No, the thousand class is not specific for your use case. The thousand class was very specific.
germayne: for ImageNet's use case, However, the convolutional layer that has been used actually has some good training. The widths.
germayne: trained in all the kernels are still super useful. So what do people say? Hey, why not we just remove the head?
germayne: Basically, I take away the fully connected layer.
germayne: Makes sense, right? This fully connected layer is hyper-focused on solving ImageNet. And what you want to do is you use people's CNN, you connect to your own fully connected layer.
germayne: And in your own fully connected layer, let's say Tengli only wants to predict cats and dogs, then you can basically have your own LEGO blocks. Same thing that we learned on Tuesday.
germayne: But your logo blocks will have two hidden layers at the end, because I just want to classify cats and dogs.
germayne: Right? So the idea here is very powerful, because you don't have to do it from scratch. So you can, you know, you can do a lot of stuff. So let's say, for example, you want to save compute. You can even freeze this layer. You can freeze the convolutional neural network layer. Basically, nothing here gets involved in backpropagation, only update the fully connected layer.
germayne: But of course, in practice, it's better to just update all your models, because your dataset is different.
germayne: Right?
germayne: Now, in practice, is this very easy? This is super easy. The libraries make it super, super, super, super easy. You just need to choose the backbone, so they call this the backbone.
germayne: Okay, so there's a few terminology that people use now, okay, so they call it the backbone.
germayne: So the backbone is basically what is the core model that was used to train the original data.
germayne: And people call the fully connected layer the head.
germayne: So people usually remove the head.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay? So, transfer learning, in practice, very easy. Conceptually, seems very difficult, but you can find core examples that do it very easily. You just need to sob the backbone.
germayne: add a bit of your own fully connected layer, and then now the question is, okay, what am I going to put for my fully connected layer? Usually people put a few non-linear… non-linear layer with a few dense layer, and then they just change the final to the number of classes, and then if, let's say, you are doing regression, you just change to one hidden… hidden unit.
germayne: Right? So this one is customizable. This one, you don't touch. You don't change anything, you just use the exact same architecture. It's going to be very complex, you're not going to go and alter anything. Of course, if you are an expert, you can feel free to drop off certain, but usually people retain most of it, and people just change the one at the back.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: Okay, I think I talked about this. Okay, so what's the benefit of doing, pre-training? Because in practice, this works.
germayne: This has been proven by many people, this works.
germayne: Right? Somehow, when people train on their dataset with million number of images, the models are already very strong. You most likely won't be able to train this from scratch.
germayne: As a normal user, you want to leverage what people has trained.
germayne: Instead, you update your model from what people has been training the model on, so this is not trained from scratch. So this is what we call the pre-trained model, okay? This has been trained by people.
germayne: This applies to everything that you know up till today, okay? If, let's say, you are interested in fine-tuning your own large language model, do you train from scratch?
germayne: You train from scratch if you have 10,000, 100,000 GPUs in your house.
germayne: And by the way, if you have 100,000 NVIDIA GPU, please tell me.
germayne: You can lend it to me as well.
germayne: Okay, if your house have that, then you can lend it to me.
germayne: Okay? So the idea here is that you don't do pre-training, you fine-tune the model. So there's a term called fine-tune. So essentially, by removing away the head, you're actually fine-tuning the model.
germayne: Okay, so when people say fine-tuner, means that you are not doing it from scratch, you're just replacing some of the head
germayne: To your own dataset.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So this is what people do, and my advice, if let's say you guys want to… I used to have a student that wanted to apply convolutional neural network. I think she works in a semiconductor company, and they want to do a lot of CNN classification on the
germayne: I think on… on… what do you call that? So they will take photo of the semiconductor parts, and if, let's say, there are some parts that is cracked, right, then they need to classify as spoiled or something. So she needed to do that, and they also started with, pre-trained models as well, okay? So that's just one example.
germayne: Okay, so obviously, pre-training doesn't work for all. In general, it's the first step to try, right? You may not know, because it depends on your data. So, try to find a paper, try to find some research paper where people have tried it, then you will know.
germayne: So there are some examples here, maybe for x-ray or MRI, maybe you have to use another model that people have fine-tuned on MRI already.
germayne: Okay? Again, this is just a general tip lah, might not be true lah. The only best way is what? So what's the takeaway?
germayne: From Neural Network and from Kaggle.
germayne: What was the takeaway?
Zac Ang: try yourself.
germayne: Let's try
germayne: I'm sure you guys know, right? I'm sure on a Saturday, you guys probably will be sharing interesting stuff.
germayne: to the whole, to the whole class, what you guys have tried. Sometimes you don't know, you just try it, just see whether it works.
germayne: Okay, I'm not going to go through too much here. Okay, so obviously there are some very popular pre-trained models, there's a lot, I'm just only listing a few here. So, again, for ImageNet, right, there's a lot, there's ResNet, so this is called the Residuer Network.
germayne: So essentially, the… this… this neural network introduces this residual flow where they basically allow this skip… skip… they basically allow the blocks to skip the gradient. So basically, it knows when to skip the block. So that's where ResNet is introduced. There's a lot… there's DensNet, there's EfficientNet.
germayne: Usually in computer vision tasks, in the past, people used a lot of these ImageNet models, but however.
germayne: as of today, April, people have already moved on to Vision Transformer.
germayne: Now…
germayne: The question to me will be that, is it… does it mean that, actually, ImageNet is outdated? No. Because, obviously, Vision Transformer is a lot more complex.
germayne: Right?
germayne: parameters. You might find a small vision transformer, but again.
germayne: I think it's best to still try out. I think Vision Transformer has been very, very popular nowadays, and actually during my grad study, I did some report where Vision Transformer actually looks at the image globally rather than locally.
germayne: Because Vision Transformer, you will start to see that, we will talk a bit about Transformer next week. Transformer doesn't look at things
germayne: You know, in a localized manner. We basically passed everything in patches, we still pass everything in patches, but when we did the diagnose for Vision Transformer, we actually see the heat map, right, that Vision Transformer actually looks at things globally.
germayne: So, let's say if you have a picture of a dog.
germayne: Right?
germayne: you know, when you were to visualize the heat map, you will see that visual transform… ImageNet actually looks at the global area.
germayne: But it was very interesting that Visual Transformer actually looks at everything. So architecture… architecturally, it's been… it is new, and a lot of very recent models all uses Vision Transformers.
germayne: But then again, if you ask me, right.
germayne: does it mean that you don't try ImageNet? I don't think so, because I think ImageNet is still very simple to train.
germayne: Right? Very simple to understand. So, you still have to try it. But these are some of the popular,
germayne: landscape for pre-trained models, so basically everybody used pre-trained models.
germayne: So now, I'm sure you guys start to get a sense that, oh, why people talk a lot about the weights, right? Now, oh, hey, for the large language model, can you give me the weights?
germayne: Now you know why, because people want to train it on their own task.
germayne: And if the weight belongs to you, it's yours to keep forever.
germayne: Okay, I think… I think basically that's all for… that's all for today. Anybody got any last questions for me for pre-training?
germayne: Can ask me anything.
Zac Ang: Sorry, so the… just to solidify the understanding, the transformer.
Zac Ang: is just like the CNN. It's just… it's just a hidden layer, like, it's just… you can swap it out for something else, is that correct?
germayne: Exactly, exactly, exactly, exactly. So, if you go back to the whole architecture thing, right?
germayne: the… the transformer is doing… obviously, transformer methodology is very different, we'll talk about it.
germayne: In the last, last lesson.
germayne: But if you think about this, right, the encoding part, right, the transformer just uses a different methodology here.
germayne: Up here. Oh, sorry.
germayne: Kill.
germayne: This part. This part is different.
germayne: A transformer doesn't do it like… like this. Transformers don't do it like, like, like… the sliding window with the convolutional is very different.
germayne: Okay? Transformers do it very differently. Transformer, think of it from a token perspective.
germayne: Okay? And we'll talk about it more in the future, but what they do is just basically swap out here lah. So the information to encode is different.
germayne: Alright.
germayne: But of course, for the image one, what they do is they break into patches lah. So what they do, right, is they underline hood, they just take, like, one patch, one patch.
germayne: And then each of the patch, right, just becomes the token. You tokenize the patch.
germayne: You basically treat it like a token.
germayne: And then you just perform the transformer's architecture.
germayne: Basically, you still do AI patches lah, so it's similar lah. Just that you don't… you don't… you no longer have a convolutional block, per se. You basically train what we call the… the attention layers.
germayne: We shall talk about it in the very last lesson.
germayne: Okay? But just telling you, it's getting more and more complex, so it will get more and more confusing.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Just now, you mentioned, ImageNet is also a pre-trained model?
germayne: Yes, yeah, so when people… so when you go and Google, right, ImageNet is a group of models trained on ImageNet data.
germayne: So basically, you have things like ResNet, DenseNet, EfficientNet. They have this net, it's because they were pre-trained on the ImageNet dataset. The millions of thousand clusters data, image data.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I knew it's a… okay.
germayne: Yep.
germayne: So, that's why I keep calling it ImageNet, but ImageNet is that data set It's just in there.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, I thought, I thought you mentioned what's a data set, but now you mentioned, like, a…
germayne: open source data set, no, it's an open source data set. A lot of models is pre-trained on ImageNet, so people call it the ImageNet models.
germayne: These are all called ImageNet models. This is Vision Transformer.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: And there are many vision transformers, by the way, there are many variants.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Just when you mentioned that, CNN is, like, it's like, okay, now there are new models taking over, overtaking, people… I'm sure there's overtaking somewhere else, but now there are new models being used…
germayne: Yep.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: The CNN is not already used, but…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I… is it because that transformer… things like transformer is overtaking, so it's not being used?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So as, as, you know, or is it, like, because it's not good enough, so it's not used?
germayne: I… I… no, no, no, no, I don't think I used the word being used. I'm just saying that I think there are newer… newer architecture.
germayne: Right? And this vision transformer is based on the transformer's
germayne: Architecture has compared to convolutional neural network.
germayne: Doesn't mean that your convolutional neural network is useless.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
germayne: doesn't guarantee that Vision Transformer outperforms CNN. Depends.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So if someone say that, you know, CNN is so passe, is it correct to say that?
germayne: Passe in what form? Parse in the academia form?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Awesome.
germayne: stay in the… in the…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, in the industry, nobody used 60 in it.
germayne: No, no, no, no, no, I don't think… I don't think that's true. I don't think that's a true… I don't think that's a true statement.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, okay, I just want to just…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Just throw down that statement, it's like, is it really…
germayne: I think it has to be… okay, again, I don't know.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because the world moved on, so why are you using this, you know?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Very good.
germayne: I cannot make the statement because I don't own the view on all the CNN. I'm not a CNN master. I'm not an image master, but let's say in my team, right?
germayne: when we build model, do you think the data scientists would say things like, okay, let's just do radiant transform, let's not do CNN? I don't think so. I don't think we will make that conclusion.
germayne: You understand what I mean?
germayne: Okay. Because CNN is still very easy to train.
germayne: I mean… I mean, not that both are difficult lah, but…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Probably less… probably cheaper,
germayne: EfficientNet is small, so EfficientNet can also be… but you can also argue that there's a small parameter for vision transformer, but I don't know, I think you have to test it. You have to try it out to see whether it works.
germayne: Right? The paradigm behind the two models are very different.
germayne: But empirically, you need to try. Is it always an empirical exercise?
germayne: You see?
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: So, let's say if you want to be very… okay, so back to Noel's question. If you want to be very cool, then you say you do transformer lah, but I think that's a wrong direction to go into.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, there's a… yeah, because it's like… because… because for now, we have a lot of models coming out, so I… are we… are we, like, you know…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, that people probably subscribe, oh, this new model will overtake a bit better, so the one will not be used.
germayne: So, though.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But then I think it's also the cost.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, so I…
germayne: So I think, I think, right, I think, right, my opinion is that usually if you have a domain, you try to see if there's any published papers that did a study on
germayne: what was tested.
germayne: But, of course, right, of course.
germayne: There are incentives for the paper to use
germayne: Transformers, because it is nicer, right? Then I publish something on CNN.
germayne: If today I were to publish a paper from my company's perspective, I have very high incentive to make the whole thing very complex.
germayne: Because I can present, right? It sounds nicer, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Does that… does that make sense?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, you wanna do, you wanna get, you wanna get eyeball, man. Right.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: You might say.
germayne: Yeah, I say I do transformer, then my transformer I do when I'm very complex. I use a thousand concurrent self-attention. I know I can do a lot of that kind of stuff to publish the paper, but if you're talking about practicality, of course you always start simple first. That's why I'm telling you that your linear regression still works sometimes. It's not like it's useless.
germayne: Right? So… I think, to answer this question, I don't think as a general statement, this… this…
germayne: there were a lot of success for ImageNet models. It's not like ImageNet models are useless. People were able to get, you know, 0.8, 0.9% of accuracy. If you think about accuracy lah, right? Again, it's a very hand-worthy thing.
germayne: Maybe, let's say you do Vision Transformer. Maybe let's say your model, you use ResNet 0.8, you do Vision Transformer 0.81 or 0.85,
germayne: Then maybe then you want to assess
germayne: based on the parameters, who is smaller. You know, there's a lot of other trade-offs that you need to make, right? You get what I mean?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Right? Maybe my vision transformer, I need the parameters to be bigger. Maybe I need more attention layers. Maybe in my convolutional, it works for me. Maybe 0.85 is actually not worth 0.8. I think that you need the business domain to answer that.
germayne: You need to answer the trade-off. I'm sure you guys saw in the Kaggle, right? I'm quite confident you guys have very complex solution. Okay, maybe, I don't know, I might be wrong. Later the one of the team just have a very simple model. But we will see you on Saturday. I think… I think on Saturday we'll discuss
germayne: how each team has been doing that. But then we can talk about, like, is it practical?
germayne: Yes, but Zach, yeah, question.
Zac Ang: I just wanted to go back to the architecture of the…
germayne: Yep.
germayne: Which one?
Zac Ang: entire thing. So… We… yeah, so we talked about the CNN as the feature layer.
germayne: Yep.
Zac Ang: And then we have the head.
Zac Ang: Yeah.
Zac Ang: I'm just thinking, then, how do you change the output? Because just so far, you've been talking about classification. So far, this is a classification problem. Like, what about other types of problems? Like, is that… what does the regression problem look like? And…
germayne: Oh, okay.
Zac Ang: Right now, we have… we… just now, the conversation is about, generation of.
germayne: Yep.
Zac Ang: image, for example, then you… do you just change the head, or, like, is it not a ReLU, or is it something else? Like, what does that look like?
germayne: Okay, there's a few questions here, so start one by one now, okay?
germayne: So, the neural network is so… is so flexible, because you are, end of the day, just adding blocks.
germayne: You're just adding blocks.
germayne: So for it to be classification, again, there's some nuance here. I'm just speaking in general, because it depends on the… it depends on the loss function you use, and PyTorch's got a lot of loss functions, so some expect certain values, some doesn't, so I'm just speaking in general. So let's say for classification, you're doing a binary classification.
germayne: you know that your binary classification, and I think I talked about it by showing the cross entropy loss, I cannot remember out of my head, but I think it's, like that, I think.
germayne: this J, this one, this N, this one over N,
germayne: I talk about this, right? And negative, I think, locked. Talk about this, right?
germayne: P-I-J.
germayne: Well, I think I talked something about this, right? The cross entropy. So you notice here, right, the cross entropy, typically, again, depends on the library, caveat here,
germayne: you can see that a classification actually needs it to be in probability. So then, you need to think about it, okay, typically what people put is they put a sigmoid layer here.
germayne: sigmoid.
germayne: Again, this is a caveat, you can change the law such that you don't put the sigmoid, but generally speaking. So here, right, if you are doing binary cross-entropy, just like every classification, you need the values to be between 0 and 1, it's a probability space. So here, right, it will map the logic to probability.
germayne: And here, you know that the last layer, you need one, so usually you put 1. Now, if it's a classic… if it's a regression, what do you do? Zach, why don't I ask you?
germayne: If it's a classification, you want to use this for… your loss now is, mean square error.
Zac Ang: I would change away the sigmoid.
germayne: Exactly.
germayne: Yeah, you have the answer already. Oh, sorry. I took the wrong eraser.
Zac Ang: But does it make sense?
germayne: No, it makes sense, yeah!
Zac Ang: How to regression an image.
germayne: No, no, no, no, no, no. CNN obviously doesn't work for… oh, wait, wait, just saying, huh?
germayne: This is also not a true statement.
germayne: Again, right?
germayne: the CNN is designed to handle data that is in this specific format.
germayne: There were papers that people formulate certain tabular data into this format, and then they say that it works.
germayne: End of the day, the model doesn't care what the data is.
germayne: You get what I mean?
germayne: But if you're talking about general tabular data, basically your data is structured. Structured data.
germayne: your data is the same as the Kaggle one.
germayne: Usually, the first thing to try is you wouldn't go and try CNN. You will try a fit-forward neural network.
germayne: And there are many, there are many types of, fit,
germayne: a feed-forward neural network, there are many types. There's also, like, you can go and Google, there's a deep and wide. I think Google created this, it's called deep and wide.
germayne: It's also for tabular data. But the point is that there's many… the course will not teach you everything. You should be equipped to go and explore on your own.
germayne: Right?
germayne: But wait, does that answer your question? The first part? I think that's the first question, right? Whether you can make it regression. So, you can see it's very flexible here. So, let's say if you want to predict multi-class.
germayne: Right, I think yesterday you soon talked about the softmax, right? So yesterday, you want to predict the digits, right? Oh, shit, I take the wrong eraser again.
germayne: You want to take the digit, right?
germayne: What do you expect from the digit?
germayne: you expect the digits to produce multiple predictions, because it's a multi-class. I know in this course we never talk about multi-class. I know we never talk about it, so I'm not going to dwell, like, too deep about it, but let's just hypothetically talk about it lah, right?
germayne: You want to do multi-class, you usually… again, multi-class, you can use cross-entropy, you can see that cross-entropy is handled for multi-classification, right?
germayne: You're only updating the laws based on the correct label.
germayne: Now, let's say in the digit… can we guys assume the digit, is it 10 classes or 9 classes? 10, right? 0 to 9, right?
germayne: 0 to 9, so thankful.
Soon | NTU: I'm just saying, yeah.
germayne: So you want to predict 10, right? What do you want? You just imagine from your head first, what do you want? You just want to predict 10 predictions for every image.
germayne: I want to predict an output of 10 prediction.
germayne: Where I want to make it multi-class. Multiclass basically means that only one label can be correct. Agreed? Because in the digit, if it's a 9, it cannot be that. Probability of 9 and probability of 1 is more than 1. Everything must sum up to 1.
germayne: So, what it means is that, okay, I know, firstly, given the picture, I have 10 different classes, 0 to 9, I want to predict
germayne: 10 different output.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: So if I want to predict 10 different output, how many should I put here?
Zac Ang: Ben.
germayne: Yeah, no, yeah.
germayne: Because the hidden dimension affects the final dimension of the output, right? The thing will be 10 by 10.
germayne: Correct? And then, what do I want to do? Usually, you want to put the softmax here. So what softmax does is that it normalizes everything so that everything sums up to 1.
germayne: Correct?
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, then what is the second question? I think you asked a few.
germayne: the ReLU thing… I cannot catch the redu one, but do I answer this, or not answer?
Zac Ang: Yeah, I think you answered the question. It's just how to adjust it to get what you want. No, the last one is more of the generation. Like, recent… nowadays, we are talking about image generation, so…
Zac Ang: Like, is this power?
germayne: Image generation is different, man, image generation uses a different architecture. It's a, it's a different, it's a different thing.
Zac Ang: Okay.
germayne: Yeah, but you are interested, you can… you can go and research on your own. You can basically just read up. It's a bit more complex. Basically, it's different, it's different, no, it's not CNN. Basically, the concept… I cannot remember the exact… is it a diffusion? They use a diffusion architecture.
germayne: It is a different one.
Zac Ang: Okay.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, again, I might be outdated. The thing changes so fast that I think Diffusion, I read up, like, a couple of months back.
germayne: I do not know today, right? If you ask me today what they use, I don't know. I don't work at OpenAI. If I know, I'll tell you guys.
germayne: Okay, but diffusion was the last few, the latest few that, as I know of.
germayne: Okay, but anyways… All good, right? Anybody got any questions? Anything else?
germayne: Yeah, I think Brian said it's still relevant, but I do not know what is the changes that they are making. I do not know if the latest one has certain tweaks to it.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: But, okay.
germayne: So, do you guys want… Soon to go through.
germayne: Otherwise, we're just putting everything on Saturday, man.
Gwen Lim: Can I be honest and say yes?
germayne: Okay, okay, so then I think soon can just go through, maybe, the CNN part lah. Then we leave one portion…
germayne: to Saturday.
Soon | NTU: Okay, let's do it.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is the… Y'all can see the screen, right? And
Soon | NTU: This is the 3.8 Jupyter Notebook, and, please…
Soon | NTU: go to this section called the CNN.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: the loss.
Soon | NTU: Section…
Soon | NTU: Okay, it's the second last section. And what we're going to do is, okay, we are going to go through
Soon | NTU: This, setting up a class for this
Soon | NTU: Okay, what do you call these class,
Soon | NTU: Okay, so it's a simple CNN, convolutional neural network, okay, to…
Soon | NTU: show you how you can actually build the CNN network, okay, in, from scratch.
Soon | NTU: Right? And then in the second part is… probably we will do it on Saturday lah, okay? So that will be also using the same kind of, data set
Soon | NTU: a different data set, okay, and we will show you how to use this, ResNet, right, residential network, to,
Soon | NTU: make use of this transfer learning, leveraging on whatever we have already obtained in the ResNet. We just customize it for
Soon | NTU: our… the CIFA dataset, which is only…
Soon | NTU: not 1,000 classes, but only 10 classes, okay? Okay, so the first part is…
Soon | NTU: This is a simple CNN. Okay, so this is a simple, classification.
Soon | NTU: model, okay.
Soon | NTU: For you to predict the, classes of these,
Soon | NTU: Okay, this is using the CIFA dataset, okay? So these are the… So-called a different layer.
Soon | NTU: Right? That we need to build, right? Convolutional, 2D, Right.
Soon | NTU: There are also 3D.
Soon | NTU: Available, okay, so for those who are keen to explore more complicated,
Soon | NTU: images in 3D, okay, so you can explore. Now, batch.
Soon | NTU: normalization, also in 2D, okay? So, just now, you have learned all these different layers in the convolutional neural network, okay? As you can see, all we need to do is just to specify the number for each of the,
Soon | NTU: Input channel, output channel, the clinical sciences, and also the…
Soon | NTU: the padding sizes, okay? So, we will leave the model, okay, to
Soon | NTU: sort out all these kernel values, and all the weights, and so on, okay, during the training, okay? So we do not need to concern with ourselves with all this nitty-gritty, what should be the kernel, so-called the value.
Soon | NTU: in the filters, like what we have seen in the, the classical, image processing technique, right? Where we have these Sobero, cany kind of, filters, okay? So this is the setup.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, and because we are going to predict 10, so-called features, yeah, so our output feature is 10, okay? So all these have to gel.
Soon | NTU: Right? The channel, the output channel, had to gel with the next convolutional 2D, right, the input.
Soon | NTU: Similar to what we have seen in the deep learning network, right, the traditional deep learning network, where your output of one layer have to be the same as the input of the next layer.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is 64, and then this is the fully connected layer, 64.
Soon | NTU: Okay, and then finally, we have the output 512 have to be here as well, in the last layer.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so this is a one-time setup, and subsequent forward pass will make use of this function to go through, okay, since we have,
Soon | NTU: 2-layer, right?
Soon | NTU: Two convolutionally, so we have the,
Soon | NTU: Okay, so we have this,
Soon | NTU: we have to specify the, activation function here. Okay, not here, but here. And then, we have to do some kind of, reshaping, right? In PyTorch, we call it Vue. In SiteScaler, we call it, reshape, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay? So this reshaping is a bit of, complicated, because of the way this PyTorch stores the dimension, okay? The number channel is not, is actually put in front, and it's not at the back. Okay, if you use, TensorFlow before, the channel is the third number.
Soon | NTU: First one is the head, height, second one is a weight, third one is a channel, but PyTorch is the other way around. The channel is the first dimension, right?
Soon | NTU: Of course, if you batch… use the batch size, the batch size will be the first dimension, followed by the channel, and then the height and the width, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, now, just now you have also, seen
Soon | NTU: why sometimes we need to use, data augmentation techniques, right? So this is a pipeline to show you what are the different, just.
Soon | NTU: only two examples. In Jermaine's slide, you actually have seen more, the other techniques, right? Rotation, flipping, cropping, and also, I think…
Soon | NTU: translation also, okay? So, the intention is to give a lot of variation and diversity of your original data, right? So that you…
Soon | NTU: will provide more input out of only a small amount of their images, okay? Because sometimes image input may be quite difficult to get, right? So you can make use of this technique to…
Soon | NTU: provide more, variation, as an input, yeah? And also, we have this very standard to tensor, right? Everything you need to do cannot be NumPy array, but you convert to a tensor.
Soon | NTU: During the training, and also normalization.
Soon | NTU: To convert all your pixel value
Soon | NTU: Into a range of minus 1 to 1.
Soon | NTU: Okay? So… here comes the very standard way of loading all your data set, right? So SIVA is,
Soon | NTU: Stand at the intersect.
Soon | NTU: In the Hugging Face.
Soon | NTU: Okay? So this is the way you…
Soon | NTU: Specify all the parameters, it will be downloaded into your, local drive, right?
Soon | NTU: Right? You'll be downloaded only once, huh?
Soon | NTU: Second time, you will… it will tell you, oh, the fara…
Soon | NTU: downloaded, okay, so there's no need to download again. Now, and also we need to, also create a data loader. As you have already seen, all the batching
Soon | NTU: all these, so-called the, especially the batching, okay, sometimes it can be very complicated if you're going to do it manually, right? Every epoch, you've got to monitor a
Soon | NTU: what is a dimension, okay? More so, you are dealing with this PyToid framework, right? Potentially, your number of dimension that you need to
Soon | NTU: look at, right? It's very, very, complicated, right? And then, next, you specify the criterion, meaning how you're going to quantify your loss. So, in this case, we're going to use,
Soon | NTU: Cross-entropy loss, because it is a multi…
Soon | NTU: multi-class, so-called declassification, right? Predicting
Soon | NTU: 10 classes, but we're going to choose only 1 out of the 10, based on the magnitude of the probabilities, right? Okay, so this is a…
Soon | NTU: code block for the train model logics, okay? So, if you look at this.
Soon | NTU: So, again, back to the 5…
Soon | NTU: Step, so-called the logic, when training the…
Soon | NTU: model, be it CNN or the, very conventional, neural network, okay?
Soon | NTU: First is…
Soon | NTU: You have to make sure you initialize your gradient, okay, because when you do the training, your gradient needs to be computed, right, on the fly, and then this is the forward pass.
Soon | NTU: Right, and then this is the last computation. This is a backward publication, and then your optimizer will
Soon | NTU: update all your weights and biases, okay? And then you… Sum up the, running…
Soon | NTU: So-called accumulate the loss of each of the,
Soon | NTU: This is an epoch, right, for each of the epochs.
Soon | NTU: And then, finally, you're going to get the,
Soon | NTU: The average for the whole training data.
Soon | NTU: I mean, we are not going to look at the batch, so-called the loss, but we are going to look at the loss for the whole data set.
Soon | NTU: I think this one has about 60,000, if I'm not wrong.
Soon | NTU: Right.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so now, when you come to evaluating model performance, right, the first thing that you need to do is to call this model… evaluate. Okay, so the intention is, as just now Jermine mentioned, right, you need to freeze
Soon | NTU: Whatever you have used during the training, some of the layers, right?
Soon | NTU: you need to freeze those layers, okay? The first one is the patch normalization, the second one is the things like your dropout, if you have used it during the training, okay? So all these things have to be static.
Soon | NTU: You know, and you have to so-called
Soon | NTU: disable it, right, during the inference, because when you predict, right, you do not like this dropout to be, like, enabled, and then start to give you a lot of random notes, okay? So.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so that is the effect of this evaluate, and then this will go through the,
Soon | NTU: Test loader, where you have to…
Soon | NTU: go through the, the batch prediction again, right? And then your prediction result will be… Accumulated here.
Soon | NTU: not accumulated, but rather you're going to compare it against the ground truth, right, which you originally stored as a label, okay? And then, the final accuracy is computed using the number of correct prediction
Soon | NTU: Over the total token.
Soon | NTU: total, training.
Soon | NTU: The train, so, sorry, the test data set.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so you come up to the… 74.
Soon | NTU: Okay, and this is the size of your… PyTorch or Tensor.
Soon | NTU: Okay.
Soon | NTU: So right.
Soon | NTU: 3232, that is the resolution of the image in the CFAR dataset, 3232, 3-channel color.
Soon | NTU: And then… D16 is the bench.
Soon | NTU: I think it's a batch of the last… The last batch size, again.
Soon | NTU: So, because, we specify it's 32, right?
Soon | NTU: So this is the batch size.
Soon | NTU: The last batch size.
Soon | NTU: Okay? Now, of course, you can…
Soon | NTU: Define some function to show the image, right?
Soon | NTU: Because you just want to see, instead of looking at the text and the number, right, you will probably want to look at, right, this is the logic to tell the,
Soon | NTU: The model to predict, and then, based on
Soon | NTU: Based on this, prediction, okay, we just want to look at, disk 10 classes.
Soon | NTU: See whether there are prediction
Soon | NTU: is correct, based on the model that we have trained, okay? So this is a logic that product orders, okay? So if you look at this, right.
Soon | NTU: Probably because of the… It's not that sharp, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so some of the prediction is, is, like, really…
Soon | NTU: supposed to be a frog, but it predicted as a deer, okay? So I… I can't figure out why. It could be a deer, why not? Right? Frog deer.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so, and then, for the transfer learning.
Soon | NTU: We will go through it on Saturday, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, so I think, based on the logic, right, so you can see we have a very consistent five-step training loops, right? And also, for the prediction evaluation, it's also
Soon | NTU: Only a few liner. Okay, compare…
Soon | NTU: I would say quite consistent, quite standard, coding structure for the PyTorch, deep learning model, right?
Soon | NTU: Okay, any, any questions, from anyone?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So this, this topic, we covered it burning already lah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Is this true?
Soon | NTU: Keep learning, years, almost daily.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, my God.
Soon | NTU: And, NLP.
Soon | NTU: To be covered is also part of the deep learning.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: If I do. Okay.
Soon | NTU: Okay, so I think for transfer learning, we also can see that, applicable into the NLP.
Soon | NTU: Right? Because as long as you have some pre-trained model, or we call it a foundation model, okay, you can always make use of the
Soon | NTU: this method, this technique, right, transfer learning, to leverage whatever other people have already done. You just have to change the head lah.
Soon | NTU: And then a debit for your owner.
Soon | NTU: use case, okay? So basically, all you need to do is to specify your… the last layer, Okay.
Soon | NTU: Which we will do it on, maybe on Saturday. So basically, you reconfigure your… your criteria, your optimizer, and also what should be the… is it going to be a logistic binary classification, or
Soon | NTU: a multicast classification.
Soon | NTU: So it's actually up to your, your, the use case.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Is it, is it wrong, or… I'm not sure, is it right.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Is it, okay, we talked about pre-training. So, pre-training is only for CNN, is it?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I know.
Soon | NTU: It is also applicable for NLP.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So only NLP and CNN image only, lah.
Soon | NTU: Oh…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, like, leisure regression, logistics, all these supervised learning, unsurvised.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That one can use pre-learning right? It doesn't make sense.
Soon | NTU: Because deep learning, potentially can go
Soon | NTU: be very complex, okay? And it will take a longer time to train
Soon | NTU: Okay. Whereas for those, very traditional machine learning algorithms, how long can it be?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, okay.
Soon | NTU: Okay, yeah, and also, I think deep learning is… you can train with lots of data. That is why you have a lot of computational, so-called intensive, computing power required during the training phase. But machine learning, even if you feed lots of data.
Soon | NTU: Your performance may not, you may not gain any benefit out of it.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So is it, is it, is it, does it make sense to have one, a new model learn from another older model so that it can get better?
Soon | NTU: For CNN, or…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I don't know, I just… I was just thinking, like, because, yeah, a lot of models keep coming out, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So let's say I have a… I've been training an old existing model, like, wow, no.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Fair a lot of things, yeah, become very good, really. And then got a new model come in.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: then I need to train it again, but instead of…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: me training it, right, I've… it looks at my old… my existing model, and then learns, and then get better, and become better than the old model.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Does it make sense?
germayne: Yes, yes, it's called… it's called distillation.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Oh, okay.
germayne: Yes, yes, there is. It works.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: It works right… that means, like, I have old, new models.
germayne: I mean, is that…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Old dog is a new, like, old dog teaching new dog, you know, like, you know.
germayne: Yes, yes, yes.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: in Shepard, right?
germayne: Yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But then, you know, the new dog, then the new dog would have to go under the… the old dog would train the new dog, you know, somehow.
germayne: there are many, there are many mechanisms to do this, Noel. So your intuition, your intuition is right. You can do, pseudo-labeling, you can do knowledge distillation, you can distill from the target label, you can train the model.
germayne: such that it fits the soft label, you can do a lot. And people are already doing that in large language models, right? Although they do it a bit differently. They just use it to generate the data to be fine-tuned from the larger model. They're already doing that already. It's just called distillation. Yeah, so your intuition is correct.
germayne: Okay. But, not taught in the class.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, okay, I just… I just… yeah, just… just thinking…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because some interviews and meetings are, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I'm not that wrong.
Soon | NTU: Yeah, yeah, that's good. You, you'll,
Soon | NTU: Very good question, always from you.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Think too much,
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, thank you, thank you.
Soon | NTU: Okay, any other questions? Otherwise, we will proceed with this.
Soon | NTU: Silo.
germayne: Okay, I think not exactly that we end early, but we end on time.
germayne: Okay, so…
germayne: Okay, so, yep, I think today is…
germayne: About the… the deep learning applied to…
germayne: image, and we learn about the inductive bias for CNN.
germayne: Correct? About the receptive field and the local… localized feature extraction.
germayne: Okay? So, I think this is the reason why specific architectures for neural networks always dominates for unstructured data, because it really, really handles the assumption of the structured data well.
germayne: If we flatten it, then basically you lose all your spatial information, because everything is flattened.
germayne: Hi.
germayne: you will start to see this same pattern for NLP as well. Why it works for NLP, because there's a specific structure that NLP requires that it's not that the other architecture doesn't work, but it just doesn't best represent the data that you're putting into the model.
germayne: Okay, so which part do you think is challenging today? I think today should be… today should… today… I think today is less heavy in terms of…
germayne: The… the new topics, but it's just more of, like, application on a newer dataset, correct?
germayne: But, I don't know, but I'll see.
germayne: How do you guys feel?
germayne: This is, like, the second last week.
germayne: Next week is, like, the last week already.
germayne: Do you guys feel that your understanding is much more as compared to before you started?
germayne: Do you guys do that?
Zac Ang: I feel like I learned that I know… I don't know a lot of things.
germayne: Hmm, but I think that's a… That's a good thing.
germayne: I think that's a good thing. This should be just a start.
germayne: This will be just a start.
germayne: Hmm.
germayne: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, the Matrix, right?
germayne: That would take… that would… that would need some self-practice.
germayne: Need to be very familiar with how to transform the shape.
germayne: How to reorder the shape.
germayne: How to flatten… Yeah.
germayne: I think the Matrix part, probably a lot of you
germayne: Let's see, let's see, let's see. We will… we will repeat these matrix things again in NLP 3.10, because sequential data is, again.
germayne: three dimension.
germayne: Yeah.
germayne: Okay, and then maybe we can see whether if there's any questions we can ask for the very last
germayne: Coaching.
germayne: Yeah, so yeah, I think it's expected to be more difficult. Please take some time to go back and understand. There should be a lot of materials online. If not, you can just ask us.
germayne: Okay, so how is today?
germayne: So you guys realized that it got easier, right, towards the back? I mean, the… the… in terms of keeping up.
germayne: I think it also shows that you guys are just getting used to it.
germayne: Okay, I'll continue.
germayne: Okay, so what was the… what was the interesting takeaway?
germayne: Or today?
germayne: What's the… what's the thing that… Blew your mind.
germayne: Mmm.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I can't think of it as a…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the… the convolution, all those dimensions, right? Is it… in a way, it's like…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Although you say it's a model, but in a way, it's like pre-processing of data also, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Is it quietly say that?
germayne: Hmm… What do you mean by pre-processed?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because it's like, you are, you are, you are, you know, like, the picture, you go, one, one by one.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Then you try to get information about, or, you know, like, you try to aggregate and get information. It's like trying to do some P-processing so that
Low Keng Teck, Noel: In the end, you can do better modeling.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, that's what people assessing data is, right? So that you can… you can… you can model, better.
germayne: I mean, it encodes it lah. I wouldn't use the word preprocess. I think I get what you're saying, but I think it's still better to think of it as encoding it to a hidden dimension.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, encoding is a word.
Zac Ang: CNN is, like, the one hot encoding that we are doing, right? Like, for linear regression.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, yeah, that's what I was thinking also.
germayne: Wait, wait, why? Why is CNN, like, one-hole encoding?
Zac Ang: Because when we do one-haul encoding, we… Create the dimensions, and we…
Zac Ang: like, just like CNO, also create dimensions.
germayne: Oh, I see, I see, I see.
Zac Ang: the one thing.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: That's what I mean by people's suicide.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Because in a way, it's like, because the head, right, is, like, really where the NN is working at.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: the one in front is really, like, you know, like, it's the input towards the NN, to the NN, right? So…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So it's, like, another way of…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: you know, processing the data, so that's why it's like… that's why I was thinking, like, pre-processing. I mean, I just thought about it.
Zac Ang: Yeah, so, like, that's how I was thinking about it also, like, so the hit part is, like, your, the linear regression dot fit.
Zac Ang: Right?
Zac Ang: In a sense.
germayne: Hmm, I see.
germayne: Oh, I think… I think it's… no, I think it's… I see where you guys are coming from. Not totally wrong, but don't think you express it out like that, lah. You just… if, let's say, that is the way for you to understand, I think it's okay. Because it's… it's… when you encode, right, it's a bit like…
germayne: generating features and signals from the input data, so not wrong. Not wrong. And then, usually, the fully connected layer is where the business logic
germayne: Comes in more relevant to your… your specific task.
germayne: for the context of the CNN, basically what the model is just learning is what kind of feature map to produce, so not wrong.
germayne: not… I wouldn't say totally off.
germayne: But, yeah.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Idea there, but explanation, not very good, okay?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah, because I think if you explain only people, but I think you don't understand the concept, so it's very important to explain it correctly also, so that…
germayne: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I understand. So you don't… so I think… I think if, let's say…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Big stuff.
germayne: No, so, so, I think, right, Noel and Zach, I think if, let's say, that's how you want to digest, I think it's okay, but you don't… let's say, if, let's say, in a setting where people ask you, right, you don't say like that.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
germayne: Because I think it will…
germayne: it will not feel correct, but it's okay to internalize like that. I think it's okay. Like, you'll find things that are relatable. Nothing to improve on,
germayne: Everybody is… Punk can't really, is it? It's right at 0P… 0 here.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: pre-holiday mood.
germayne: So what, there's nothing?
germayne: Nothing to improve on.
germayne: Okay, la ba, have a good break, have a good break tomorrow. Just to tell you guys, FYI, while you guys are typing.
germayne: the Kaggle will officially close at 12 midnight on Saturday.
germayne: So Saturday, 12 midnight, and the private leaderboard will be released 9AM on Saturday. So 9am, you guys will see the result.
germayne: Okay, last submission will be 12.
germayne: Results will be out at 9.
germayne: Okay, so just nice, we start the class with the results.
germayne: Fun rate.
germayne: I set it as such.
germayne: Okay?
germayne: What other things, we link back to 3.1?
germayne: Oh, why do we need to go back to 3.1?
germayne: This one doesn't go back to 3.1, right?
germayne: Hmm.
germayne: Okay, okay, I think that's, that's all, that's all. I think we can close for today.
germayne: So, okay, so on Saturday, we will… we will finish the last part for the notebook, and what will happen on Saturday is we will just… we will do a Kaggle unofficial sharing between all the groups that win, because I'm also very curious.
germayne: what was done. So don't need to prepare a slide or what, but I think the teams can just come out and share. We can just have a friendly discussion on what you guys tested. What I'll do is I'll create certain framework so that we know what to share, like, what are the different portions that was tested.
germayne: So I'll share that framework, and then we will invite the teams to come and share that, because I'm sure everybody wants to know what worked, right? Like, what is the different themes that… what's the different thing that people have tried?
germayne: Okay, and then there will be some, some, some additional gifts lah.
germayne: Okay? For the, for the top, top winners.
germayne: Okay? All good. Anybody got any last question for me?
germayne: Do I have? Go ahead, Dan.
Josiah Ho: The keger will get disqualified one or not.
germayne: What do you mean? We're gonna do something weird, is it? Why, why would it get disqualified? I mean, don't lah, don't, don't, don't do anything weird. Okay, if you feel like something is off, right, then don't do it.
germayne: Please.
germayne: The purpose is to try… to try, like, to… to do all whatever that you have learned from the lesson.
germayne: Okay, it's a fun… it's just a fun… just a fun exercise.
germayne: Okay, so, take note, last submission will be Saturday 12, so Friday night to 12, then we'll stop, so that you can get the rest, then the result will only be released in the morning.
germayne: Okay? So, please have fun, and… yeah, have a good holiday, everyone, tomorrow. I'll see you guys on Saturday.
Josiah Ho: Thank you, bye-bye.
germayne: Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you so much.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Thanks for…
germayne: Thanks, Alvin.
Shilpa Kangya: Bye.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: Bye, Jamie.
germayne: Bye-bye, bye-bye.
germayne: Danny, all good?
germayne: Oh, okay, okay, thanks soon, bye-bye.
Soon | NTU: Hey, bye-bye.